Then let us begin,
pitiful boy.
Thrall of Heart-under-blade.
Wait, before we do that, let's go over the conditions.
If I win—
you'll give Kiss-shot's right leg back to me.
Is that fine with you?
If I win—
you'll tell me Heart-Under-Blade's whereabouts.
Fine by me.
Then let us begin.
NISIOISIN
Original Work
Araragi Koyomi
Kamiya Hiroshi
Ebara Masashi
Irino Miyu
Ohtsuka Houchu
Kizumonogatari
Hot-blooded Chapter
Aikido
from
Step One
How to Play Baseball
Dramaturgy is a vampire.
V-Vampire?
He's—a vampire?
Could ye not tell by the sight of him?
Or are there humans who boast his frame?
Flashback
I've never heard tell of any in my five hundred years.
But,
why would a vampire be a vampire hunter?
That doesn't make sense.
Vampires who slay their own kind
are not particularly uncommon.
An eye for an eye,
a tooth for a tooth,
a vampire for a vampire.
Right?
Is that you, Araragi?
Hanekawa...
Nope.
I'm not giving you a look today.
Spin
Wh-Wh-Wh-What do you
m-m-mean
by that?
I d-d-don't
understand
—stand —stand —stand —stand .
Unfortunately, I don't know what you're talking about.
Hmm. What?
So you forgot what happened?
Even after you saw my panties.
After staring right at them.
Staring
N-No!
This is a misunderstanding, it's all a misunderstanding!
I only saw the lining of your skirt.
R-Right...
That was the only thing I was paying attention to—the lining of your skirt.
That's pretty perverted in its own way.
Hanekawa...
What are you doing here?
Hmm?
Going for a walk? I guess?
What,
at this hour?
What're you reading Araragi?
Is that a book about baseball?
What, is that book something you don't want me seeing?
Hey, could it be something dirty?
Don't be stupid.
I've never even touched printed matter as crass as that.
I wouldn't want to sully my soul.
Well, yep, that's about it.
Wait, why are you leaving so soon?
We should take the chance to talk some more.
Talk...
About what?
Hmm? Right...
So Araragi,
what did you study today?
I focused mostly on math.
M-Math, huh...
U-Unfortunately, all I studied today was Spanish.
Spanish?
Too bad, I don't know much Spanish.
Th-That really is too bad.
Yeah.
I know just enough for basic conversations.
Spasibo!
Spasibo is Russian.
Also, spasibo doesn't have any connotation of wonderful if you wanna know.
You shouldn't do that!
You need to remember what words mean.
Y-Yeah...
You really do know everything, don't you?
Not everything.
I just know what I know.
Anyway,
learning is a really great thing!
Every day is a new lesson for all of us.
That's a pretty good one, Araragi.
So let's think about something more constructive.
Yeah!
Like how to make society a better place.
You're right.
Okay, what might we do to get rid of bullying?
Hanekawa...
Why don't you head home already?
I was about to do the same, anyway.
Well, you don't have to tell me. That was my plan to begin with.
You shouldn't wander around at night.
You might run into a vampire, you know?
Actually, I was kind of hoping I would.
I guess it's only a rumor—
but I was thinking I just might get to meet a vampire.
Why?
Why would you want to meet a vampire?
Oh, I don't have anything particular in mind.
I'm at that age where you hanker after something out of the ordinary, that's all.
I thought I'd meet a vampire,
then have a little chat—
Bullshit!
Huh?
S-Sorry!
It seems like I touched a nerve there.
No. You're the one who gets on my nerve.
It just pisses me off...
That arrogance of yours.
I'm alone because I want to be alone.
Stop following me.
A-Araragi, why are you saying these things all of a sudden?
Weren't we having fun talking until just a second ago?
It wasn't fun for me at all.
I was only pretending it was fun.
I was only after your fortune.
M-My family isn't that rich, you know?
Kishi Memorial Gymnasium
I don't know if this is some way for you to get good letters of recommendation,
but what's a model student like you doing talking to a washout like me?
You might enjoy whatever feelings of superiority you get from this,
but I can't bear you standing there and feeling sorry for me.
Hanekawa Tsubasa
And don't mess with people's phones without their permission.
Huh?
Flashback
Shit....
Huh?
Delete all 1 contacts?
Deleting
Deleted
So get out of my face.
Flashback
All right.
Fine.
That must have done something—
to up my intensity as a human.
I was stronger.
That's why...
That's why my...
battle with Dramaturgy—
my mission to return Kiss-shot's right leg to her—
would surely go off without a hitch.
Right now, that was what I needed to do most.
My heart aching...
was not a problem.
March 31st
What's wrong?
Are you just going to run, thrall of Heart-under-blade?
Don't call me weird names.
How's that?!
What are you up to, Dramaturgy?
It is as it appears. I surrender.
Smashed with that thing, with your strength, the damage would be tremendous—
it would take me two full days to regenerate.
You seem to have misunderstood something.
Not many vampires have the ability to heal damage instantaneously.
You belong to a wholly different catergory.
After all, you are Heart-under-blade's thrall.
In spite of the gap in raw ability,
I thought my experience gave me a chance, for now, to beat you—
but it seems impossible.
Netting you is beyond me.
No—wait.
Would you be satisfied, then, if I said this?
I will never lay my hands on you again,
so please spare my life.
In any case...
that takes care of the right leg.
What was that just now?
Hey, Araragi.
I was too far away to see clearly,
but... weren't you just doing something out of a fantasy novel?
What's it have to do with you?
Rather,
why are you tailing me again?
I don't get it.
I told you not to follow me around.
Stop pretending to be my friend.
You're not the type to say that kind of thing, are you, Araragi?
I feel bad that I'm making you say these things.
It must mean that you're in such a tough spot,
that your only option is to say them, right?
I'm sorry for taking so long to notice.
Sorry!
But, I want to help if that's the case.
You're really pushy, you know that?
You're reading too much into things.
I was just bored of hanging out with you.
I prefer to be alone.
Liar.
You're not a misanthrope or the world-weary type, Araragi.
I can figure that much out!
Flashback
At least, you seemed to be having fun when you were talking to me.
Like I said, I was only after your fortune!
Like I said
And like I said, my family isn't that rich!
Then I was only after your toddy!
I don't drink, and you shouldn't either!
No, I'm telling you I was only after your body!
Like I said
Body
Which is it, my toddy or my body?!
Your body!
Fine then, I'll make up with you if you show me your panties again!
Okay.
Is this okay?
Can you see them all right?
Do you want me to take off my blouse, too?
Hey...
I said some horrible things. I'm sorry!
Please be my friend.
He really did give it back.
That's what a negotiator is for.
Here, Heart-under-blade.
Wait, what are you going to do?
That leg doesn't match your current size.
You aren't just swapping them, are you?
I do this.
Don't be standing there gaping, fools.
Leave me to myself as I eat.
Where are thy manners?
By the way, Oshino.
What is it?
Flashback
My left arm was blown clean off by Dramaturgy.
But I recovered instantly.
So why didn't Kiss-shot's limbs regenerate at all?
Flashback
Don't you think it's because Heart-under-blade
had lost nearly all of her immortal force by the time you met her?
Don't you think so too?
Well, yes, I did think of that.
But during my fight,
Flashback
when my arms were cut off,
the old ones disappeared by the time I was healed.
So I thought maybe Kiss-shot's limbs might have disappeared, too.
But that wasn't the case either.
Then, how come—
they didn't regenerate, and they didn't disappear...
That kid is a rare breed, Araragi.
Those guys wanted her body intact—
to steal it and make it their own.
Those guys divided the body from the limbs did they not?
In other words, it wasn't her limbs that they took from her,
but also her existence as a vampire itself.
Oshino.
Am I...
really going to be able to become human again?
I don't see why not, as long as you can get back all of Heart-under-blade's arms and legs.
Isn't that what the kid said?
Well, that's the thing,
isn't there the possibility that Kiss-shot is lying?
I can see how she might be in order to get her limbs—
Hey.
You shouldn't distrust her like that.
Poor girl.
But...
Saying that about someone who saved your life?
I can't believe how ungrateful you are.
Flashback
What's with that face, Araragi?
Something good happen to you?
Don't talk like you see through me.
April 1st
So maybe... it's my fault.
Huh?
What is?
Your run-in with a vampire.
Rumors have a funny way of coming true, right?
Especially for ghost stories and stuff.
They say rumoring has a way of—having them find their way to you.
But that doesn't make sense.
You told me about the rumor, so you'd have to run into a vampire too.
I don't have to,
it's probably just that your chances increase...
Besides, I have, haven't I?
You, Araragi.
Putting the talk about rumors aside,
yesterday you were going out of your way to look for a vampire, if anything.
Why were you?
You said you wanted to talk to one or something.
Well, it wasn't that I was seriously looking for a vampire.
I was stamping my feet for something that I know doesn't exist.
How do I say this?
Maybe I've been going in circles and wanted a change in my life?
Haven't you ever wanted a change in your life?
A change, huh?
It was just my way of trying to escape from reality.
I'd love to get back to reality, myself.
I'm sure you'll be able to.
Like I said, I want to help,
but considering how outrageous this situation is,
it doesn't feel like there's much I can do.
That's not true.
Those clothes and daily essentials are a great help.
Oh, it's nothing.
Why don't you hurry up and get changed, then?
Your clothes are a mess.
Yeah, you're right.
Um...
Well, that is...
I guess I could at least change my shirt.
Was medium okay?
Y-Yeah...
I didn't know which you wanted, so I got you both boxers and briefs.
What's the matter?
Not going to change?
I will...
Wait a sec.
I knew it.
I thought so yesteday too.
Your body's a little different, Araragi.
Something seemed a bit off when I saw you from behind yesterday.
So it was your muscles.
You also seem thinner, more cut.
Of course thy body has changed, ye've become a vampire.
Our powers of healing work to keep our bodies in optimal condition.
Excuse me for a bit.
Just from touching though,
you still feel the same as other humans.
But with subtly more muscle elasticity.
"The same as other humans?"
Hanekawa, does that mean...
You've touched the bodies of other men?
No! No! No!
There's no way I would do that!
Th-That's right!
I was speaking from imagination, not experience.
I shouldn't do that.
Hurry and put on that shirt.
O-Okay.
It looks great on you.
Thanks for all the help, Hanekawa.
I'll definitely pay you back.
You don't have to. This is really all I can do, anyway.
All you can do? It's more than enough.
Thank you. I mean it.
O-Oh, stop it.
That's what friends are for, right?
Don't hesitate to let me know
if there's anything else you want me to do, Araragi.
This is about everything I can do at the moment, though.
Oh, right. Do you want me to clean this classroom?
It looks like a total mess.
It's fine. It was like this when we found it.
That's no reason to leave it a mess.
We ought to start where we can, and—
Hm?
Huh?
What's this?
Flashback
I had forgotten to tell thee.
That bag thou had so preciously clung to was on the side of the station,
so I brought it here with me for thee.
Y-You goddamned traitor!
Um...
When you encountered that vampire, you were...
on the way back from the bookstore, right?
On March 25th?
The night of the day we first ran into each other?
So, what's this?
April 4th
Episode is a half-vampire vampire hunter...
Flashback End
Well, even I know that much vampire terminology,
but couldn't you give me some more details, Kiss-shot?
I forget.
Hey!
One moment. I'll remember in no time.
I remember.
What did you remember?
That Episode fellow...
detests vampires with a passion.
He detests them?
Why?
He's half vampire, right?
Well, to put it simply,
'tis because half-vampires are not accepted into the world of vampires.
Nor is that reason enough for them to be accepted into the human world.
And so,
they hate their vampire blood.
Episode in particular seems to have a strong hatred of vampires.
While work may have driven Dramaturgy, emotions move Episode.
Gotta love it.
Cracks me up, it really does.
Old Dramaturgy finding himself on the wrong end of a hunt going after a brat like you.
Well, I'll show those guys how to hunt their prey.
I'm warning you,
don't think I'll go easy.
I hate picking on the weak,
but I love picking on the evil.
Am I evil?
Of course you are!
You're a monster.
Monster
Aren't you—
Huh?
Aren't I what?
If there's something you want to say, spit it out!
No, it's nothing...
There's nothing I want to say.
Let's get started.
C-Cross?
Araragi!
You can't give up yet!
The opponent turns into mist—
He turns into mist, so that means—
Hanekawa...
Hanekawa, Hanekawa, Hanekawa!
Be quiet, Araragi.
Get it together...
You're dealing with mist.
Gotta love it.
Mist, in other words, water.
What would happen if I dumped sand on you?
Okay, enough.
Keep going and you won't be a human anymore.
O-Oshi— O—
Y-You were—
What about Hanekawa?!
Don't yell.
So spirited, Araragi.
Something good happen to you today?
Well,
I'm sorry to dampen your spirits,
but the fight's been decided.
Just look, he's passed out.
But... but...
Hanekawa...
Hanekawa!
Yeah, I saw.
You saw? But why—
Why didn't you stop her?!
It's not included in the bill.
I've only taken on negotiating with three vampire hunters.
Anything beyond that requires a separate fee.
I can't get mixed up with ordinary people.
Then tell me that from the beginning!
If you had—
You could pay for missy class president's fee.
How about another two million?
Two million?
I would've paid three!
This isn't a game, Oshino!
It's no game. It's about gain, Araragi.
Game
Gain
We have a deal. Three million yen.
I'll give you a hint, then.
Try using your head, Araragi.
What's that immortal body of yours for?
Hanekawa...
Araragi?
Why are you rubbing your cheek against my stomach, and so fondly too?
Also, my uniform is torn.
Should I chalk that up to you?
My bad, Hanekawa.
Stay still for a bit more.
April 5th
My body feels quite a bit better.
I dare say that my immortality has nearly returned.
Oh... so are you at a point where you might, you know,
take care of the next battle?
Unfortunately, I seem as yet unable to use my skills as a vampire.
It has become harder for me to die, but that is the extent of it.
Perhaps I would be able to fight Dramaturgy,
but even Episode might prove too much for my current state.
Let alone Guillotine Cutter.
Flashback
Guillotine Cutter, huh?
Am I right to think that he's human?
Indeed. He is neither a vampire like Dramaturgy,
nor a half-vampire like Episode.
Flashback
He is a plain, pure and simple, human.
He didn't seem all that plain to me.
Mm. True.
He's what ye'd call... a holy man.
Don't tell me he's some kind of Christian spec ops.
So close, yet so far.
But... whatever else he may be, he's still a human, right?
No matter what methods he uses, won't he still be no match for a vampire?
Neither a vampire, nor a half-vampire,
but a human has taken on vampire hunting as his specialty.
If anything, it should be cause for concern.
In fact, has he not taken both my arms from me?
Still, it was because I erred in not taking them seriously.
I felt a tad under the weather, too.
If work is what drives Dramaturgy,
and emotions Episode,
then 'tis duty that spurs Guillotine Cutter.
As odd as it is for me to say this, faith is quite a handful.
Hanekawa, how's the wound on your stomach?
The wound—well,
there's nothing left of the wound.
I see.
Here, show me.
What 'here'?
Hey, Araragi-kun, would you like a sandwich?
This one has tomato.
No, I'm fine.
Oh?
Here, Araragi-kun.
Coca Cola.
Thank you.
And for me, I have Diet Cola.
If your body naturally puts on muscle,
does that mean you can take as many calories as you want without getting fat.
That'd make any girl jealous.
I wonder...
If anything, it's that I don't feel hungry.
Like, I'd be fine if I didn't eat.
Don't vampires feed on blood for their meals?
Oh yeah, that's right.
Speaking of, Araragi. Do you ever get urges to suck blood or anything?
Hm?
Well, now that you mention it, no.
Hanekawa.
You should stop coming here.
Well, I thought you might say that.
Please, I don't want you to feel hurt,
it's not like last time.
Well, last time...
was partly about not wanting to get you mixed up in it, of course,
but a lot of it was my not being able to keep my emotions in check.
I took it out on you, and I regret it.
But this time is different.
How's it different?
When Episode's cross took a chunk out of your side yesterday,
I lost myself.
Flashback
I could feel the blood rising to my head.
I thought I'd die.
Mine?
Mine.
I talked to you about my intensity as a human, right?
You getting wounded hurt like it was me who'd gotten wounded.
No—
It hurt more.
Hanekawa, I'm...
I'm not so desperate to become a human again that I'd do it at your expense.
At my expense?
I don't feel like you're treating me in such a way, Araragi.
But don't you wonder what you're doing?
Wasting your spring break for my sake
at an important time in your life—
And nearly dying in the process.
Doesn't that make you wonder what you're doing?
N-Not at all!
I just don't get it.
I'm not confident that I'd be able to help you in the same situation.
I wouldn't be able to go that far.
Showing myself to a loose cannon like him—
if I had a body that could die—
But you did it like it was nothing.
You...
scare me.
You're too bright...
You shouldn't sacrifice yourself!
Please, I'm not saying that to hurt you,
I just can't understand why you're going this far for me.
I can't figure it out,
how you'd be this devoted
to a classmate you only got to know the other day.
It's like you're a saint.
But your self-sacrifice is way too heavy a burden for me.
I'm not big enough to bear it.
It's not self-sacrifice.
It isn't self-sacrifice!
Then what is it?
Self-satisfaction.
You're misunderstanding me, Araragi.
I'm not that good of a person, and I'm not that strong of a person.
I'm just doing what ever I feel like doing.
I doubt there are many people out there as self-absorbed as I am.
I'm sneaky, and I think I'm tough.
Enough to creep you out, actually.
But,
if my presence is making things harder for you,
then that really is putting the cart before the horse.
If you say so, then it must be time I leave.
It does look like there's nothing left for me to do.
No, there is something you can do.
Wait for me.
At that school, once the new year starts.
I'm looking forward with all my heart to chatting with you again.
What's that the sound of?
My hearth throbbing.
Girls come with a sound effect for that?!
That was really close.
I nearly developed something for you just now.
What do we mean by 'developed' here, like a new drug or a beach resort?
So that's the line you use to sweet-talk girls.
No no. I don't even know what you mean,
I barely even talk to girls.
Listen to you, acting all tough and uninterested. Like you never bought those dirty magazines.
Sheesh.
I'll let you borrow these.
Give them back when we meet next school year.
Araragi, you like panties, don't you?
U-Um...
Well, if you don't want them—
No! No! No!
I never said I didn't.
Wanting it or not isn't the issue here, is it?
What was that?!
I give these back to you when we meet next school year, right?!
Sorry.
I can't give these back.
Excuse me?
I mean, I'm never giving these back.
I'm passing these down from generation to generation as the Araragi family heirloom.
I certainly didn't sign up for that.
These panties have parted from your flesh for eternity.
How dare you!
I won't give them back,
but mark my words.
I will return this favor.
If there's ever a time you need me,
and even if there's nothing I can do,
I promise I'll be there.
As of today, it will be my life's mission
to repay you.
Just give my panties back!
So, now I'm going to have to go home,
panty-less, and in a skirt,
with its low security rating.
Araragi, compared to that, beating this Guillotine Cutter person
can't be that hard, right?
Point taken!
Then good luck!
Good luck!
Until next school year.
Sorry, I messed up.
Missy class president got kidnapped.
What should I do?
What is it that I need to do?
Araragi,
forget about your humanity.
Araragi!
I'm sorry, Araragi. I...
What are you going to do to Hanekawa?
I'm not going to do anything.
As long as you don't do anything.
While I may not have superhuman strength like your kind,
I have trained quite a bit.
A single girl?
Killing her would be easy.
And you call yourself human?
Hanekawa.
It'll be okay.
I promise I'll save you.
How unpleasant.
I am not so tolerant as to allow myself to a be a willing participant in your show of high school friendship.
Let it begin.
Begin?
How?
All you need to do is put your hands up and say 'I give up' the moment the battle begins.
In other words, the match will be decided as soon as it begins.
Okay.
Araragi!
You don't need to care about me!
How could I not care about you?!
I told you,
I'm not so desperate to become human again that I'd do it at your expense.
Araragi,
forget about your humanity
Looking at myself...
I certainly wasn't human.
I had abandoned my humanity.
That much I understood.
I was already—
a monster.
Kizumonogatari
Cold-blooded Chapter