What Happened that Day
SSSS.GRIDMAN
Voice Drama
— Episode 9.9999 —
Okay, now let's go over there!
Come on, you're pushing yourself too hard.
I'm not forcing myself or anything!
After this let's head to Ikspiari and line up at Gong Cha, then go to Moreru Mignon, okay?
Right. Yeah. I got this!
Yeah, you're definitely forcing yourself—
Nah, I'm really not. This is just the first date we've been on in a while, Akane.
Still doing your best for me even though you have amnesia, huh?
Well... I try.
Thanks.
But, that said...
What's up?
Even though you have amnesia I wish you'd at least remember your girlfriend, you know?
Yeah, um... I'm really sorry about that.
Dummy...
You know... It's just so weird that someone so cute suddenly told me they were my girlfriend.
I thought you were trying to trick me.
Huh? What do you mean?
It's just, I thought it was some kind of prank—
Not that! What you said before it!
Huh...? Well, yeah, having someone as cute as you tell me you're my girlfriend is—
Yup! I'm your cute girlfriend, Akane, that's me! Yaaay!
Yaaay!
Wait, hold on... what're we even doing?
We always do stuff like this. You really don't remember?
Did we really?
Don't you like it?
Well, I don't not like it...
It's kinda fun, even.
I know, right?
So, while we're talking about it...
Hmm?
We are, um... our relationship is like, you know, we're lovers, right?
Yeah, you could call us that.
So... Uh... Just exactly how close have we been with each other?
What do you mean "how close"?
Well, uh, I'm not asking for solid answers like how far we've been, it's just...
Wait, you seriously don't remember that?
Well, I do have amnesia, so—
You're not lying?
You're saying you even forgot something as important as that?
You don't remember what happened that day? You're the worst!
What happened that day...?
Oh no, this sounds like it was something really important.
I'm going home.
No no, wait!
Not a chance.
That's not— That's not what I meant!
Let go of me!
Akane! ...Akane?
Hmm?
Just kidding!
Really, I was just joking!
I said I was kidding! Of course there's no way I could forget something that important! Right?
Oh come on, you really scared me! I actually believed you!
Totally fooled you, huh?
Jeez... You're so mean!
If you really did forget I would've stabbed you to death.
Hah... I hope that's just a joke.
So... you do remember what happened that day, right? Honest?
Uh-oh... This could be bad! Remember! I need to remember!
You do remember what happened that day, right?
Totally!
Uh, Akane, listen...
Hmm?
I want you to hit my head really hard, okay?
Wait, what? You're scaring me...
Uh, it's fine, just hit me as hard as you can!
Huh? For real?
Yeah! For real! Just do it!
Huh...?
My only chance is that the impact will jog something in my brain!
If it doesn't, I'll get stabbed.
Uh... If you say so...
Okay... I'm gonna hit you super hard, ready?
Yes! Please do it!
Actually if I don't have anything in my hand I might hold back, mind if I use this jar?
Jar?
You see, this jar is made of a kind of metal from outer space called happy cosmonium...
Happy cosmo—? Uh, well... okay then. Sure, go ahead.
Alright, here I go...
Yes, please!
You alright?!
Ah... I'm fine, I'm fine.
Really?
Yeah, totally fine. I actually do remember what happened that day.
Eh? We don't have to talk about that right now, no need to force yourself.
It was before summer and on the day we had the ball game rally.
We were talking with each other in the classroom during the break, right?
And it was before you dyed your hair, Akane. Back when it was long and black.
You told me you were planning to give one of the head bands to a friend who wasn't able to come.
Right.
While we stood there listening to the loud cheers from the gym...
Your black hair was swaying in the wind, just like the curtains in the classroom.
That's when I realized I...
I like you, Akane.
That wasn't me.
I said that wasn't me.
I wasn't there the day of the ball game rally.
Uh, then...
Also, I haven't changed the length of my hair since I started school.
It was never black, either.
Wait, what? Then who was I...
I'm gonna stab you after all, Hibiki-kun.
Huh?
Whoa, wait, wait, Akane! Hold on a sec! That's not it!
My memory's gotta be messed up—
You'd better be ready, this is gonna hurt a lot!
Just kidding!
Did I scare you?
Oh come on... Really?! You really did scare me!
Gotcha!
Give me a break...
Of course I wasn't gonna stab you!
It's not like you have to remember every little thing, you know?
We can make more memories in the future.
I'm really sorry...
...and thank you.
Then, I'll be in your care from now on.
Yeah. Same for me.
But really, if I did get stabbed by someone as cute as you,
it might just be worth it to see their smile, you know?
Eh? What was that?
Like I said, a girlfriend as cute as you—
Yup! Your cute girlfriend, Akane, is gonna stab right through your heart!
Yaaay!
Really, what're we even doing?
I got no idea!