Monochrome Inverted
Kizumonogatari
Iron-blooded Chapter
March 25th
Naoetsu
Private
High
School
Entrance
Naoetsu
Private
High
School
Entrance
Um...
I... I didn't see anything.
Naoetsu
Private
High
School
Entrance
Naoetsu
Private
High
School
Entrance
I've been thinking, you know,
for something that's meant to hide what you don't want seen,
skirts really are low security.
Maybe I need the firewall of a pair of bike shorts after all?
Wh-Who knows...
Well, I should get going.
Wait up a second!
You're a fast walker.
I could hardly catch up to you,
Araragi.
Araragi
Why do you know my name?
What? Of course I know it.
We go to the same school.
Written with an "a" from the Buddhist "antigod,"
Antigod
a "ra" or two for good measure,
ra
rara
and a "gi" from "ginkgo tree", too.
gi
Your given name is Koyomi, as in the character for 'calendar', right?
Koyomi
Right? Thus we have Araragi Koyomi.
Araragi Koyomi
You're Hanekawa, right?
Hanekawa Tsubasa.
Hanekawa Tsubasa
Wow!
I'm amazed that you know someone like me.
Hanekawa Tsubasa, who during final exams of the first trimester of our second year
got only one answer wrong, a fill-in-the-blank, across every subject, even PE and art.
What? That's... hey, why do you know so much about me?
Wait... are you stalking me, Araragi?
Maybe putting it that way makes it sound like I have too much of a persecution complex?
Not really.
I heard about you from an alien friend.
What? You have friends, Araragi?
Ask about the alien part first!
Ah, well,
you're always alone, so I had the impression that you lived up in a world apart from everyone else.
Well, you're right that I don't have any friends.
Which makes you so famous that even a friendless loser knows who you are.
Oh, stop it.
I don't like jokes like that.
Say, Araragi.
Do you believe in vampires, Araragi?
What about vampires?
Well, there have been some rumors lately that there's a vampire here in town.
They say not to walk around alone at night.
What a vague... and phony rumor.
They say the vampire is a beautiful blond woman,
but with eyes so cold they make your spine freeze.
And that makes them a vampire?
Couldn't she just be a normal person who stands out because she has blond hair?
But, according to them, when she was under a street lamp, though her hair was blindingly bright...
she didn't have a shadow.
Still, this happened at night.
It's not like street lamps make shadows unmistakably clear.
Yeah, I think it's a ridiculous rumor, too.
But personally, if there's a vampire, I'd like to meet her.
I think it'd be neat if someone like that existed—an existence greater than humans.
An existence greater than humans? Like a god?
It doesn't have to be a god.
Because in so many ways, where's the reward otherwise?
Oh no, oh no.
You know, Araragi, you're surprisingly easy to talk to.
My tongue slipped and I feel like I ended up saying something that didn't make much sense just now.
It's strange that you don't have any friends when you're this easy to talk to.
Why don't you make some?
Making friends would lower my intensity as a human.
What?
Sorry, I don't really understand.
Er... well, you know, it's like...
In other words, if I had friends, I'd have to start worrying about them, right?
If my friends were hurt, I'd feel hurt too,
and if they felt sad, I'd feel sad too.
You end up with more weak points, so to speak.
I think that's the same as becoming weaker as a person.
But you have fun when your friends have fun,
and you're happy when your friends are happy,
so it's not all about becoming weaker, right?
No.
I'd feel envious when my friends were having fun,
and jealous when they were happy.
How petty of you.
Leave me alone.
Naoetsu
Private
High
School
Entrance
Naoetsu
Private
High
School
Entrance
I was thinking of going to the library.
Do you want to come with me?
Why?
What're you going to do at the library?
What else? Study.
What else?
Sorry, but I'm not enough of an oddball to study on my own during spring break
when we don't even have homework.
But we'll be taking entrance exams only next year, you know?
Naoetsu
Private
High
School
Entrance
Naoetsu
Private
High
School
Entrance
Entrance exams?
I'll be happy if I can graduate at all.
It's too late for me, I'm a lost cause.
Araragi, do you have a cell phone?
Well, yeah. Of course.
Can I borrow it?
Thanks. Here.
Naoetsu
Private
High
School
Entrance
Naoetsu
Private
High
School
Entrance
I added my number and email.
Hanekawa Tsubasa
Too bad for you. You just made a friend.
What the hell?
Naoetsu
Private
High
School
Entrance
Naoetsu
Private
High
School
Entrance
Flashback
Hanekawa Tsubasa
Departures
Platform
Express
Local
Naoetsu North
Naoetsu Central
Naoetsu South
Shinjuku
Ginza
Oizumi-gakuen
New York
Indeed,
it shall be thy privilege to aid me.
Can ye not hear me?
I am telling thee that it shall by thy privilege to aid me.
H-Hey...
Are you okay?
I-I'll get an ambulance right away...
An ambulance?
I have no need of such.
Instead...
Give me thy blood.
Do you believe in vampires, Araragi?
They say the vampire is a beautiful blond woman,
but with eyes so cold they make your spine freeze.
My name is Kiss-shot Acerola-orion Heart-under-blade,
the iron-blooded, hot-blooded, yet cold-blooded vampire.
I shall consume thy blood as mine own flesh.
So, give me thy blood.
Isn't a vampire
supposed to be... immortal?
I've lost too much blood.
Neither regeneration nor transformation is possible for me in this state.
Unless something is done, I will die.
A worthless human such as thee should be honored to become my flesh and blood.
B-Blood?
Can't you settle for a transfusion or something?
H-How much do you need?
For the time being, I will be tided over with thy body's worth.
Oh, just my body's...
What is the matter?
Thy blood. Give me thy blood.
Hurry... Hurry up.
Hurry. Why do ye dally, laggard?
It's fine.
I can get away.
Can ye imagine any honor greater than this?
I can get away from this.
Just run.
That will let me
escape this reality.
What?
Y-Ye jest...
Ye... fail to aid me?
No!
No! No! I don't wanna die!
I don't wanna die! I don't wanna die!
Help me! Help me, please!
Please, I beg you!
Help me...
No!
I'm sorry!
I would die.
She's a monster!
She's a vampire!
I don't have to help her.
Right?
Of course I know that!
Don't give up, stupid!
S-So you're okay with this?
Of course I'm not.
Damn it.
Why?
How did things end up this way?
I swear, I'll make something better of my next life.
I'll be smart, and everything bad that happens will be everyone else's fault.
I'll be reborn into someone like that.
And that's why, I'll help you.
Suck my blood.
I'll give it all to you.
Don't leave a drop behind.
Wring me dry.
Thank you.
Was it a dream?
Surprise
H-Hey!
W-Wake up.
Just five more minutes...
Five minutes
C-C'mon, I said wake up!
Not feeling it right now.
Feeling it
How long are you gonna sleep?!
4.6 billion years
4.6 billion years or so.
That'd be enough time for another Earth!
March 28th
Two whole days had gone by?
You fool!
Honestly.
What sort of dunce runs out under the sun with no warning?
Any average vampire would've evaporated in the blink of an eye.
Never go into the daylight again.
With thy immortality turned to a curse, ye'll be stuck in an eternal loop—burn, recover, burn recover.
Ye'd live through hell.
If an undead vampire could be said to live.
Undead?
Y-You mean you're...
Flashback
Indeed I am Kiss-shot Acerola-orion Heart-under-blade.
You may call me Heart-under-blade.
400 years have passed since I last created a thrall,
and this was but my second time,
yet it seems to have went well,
judging by those regenerative powers.
Th-Thrall?
Thrall
Indeed! And as a result, ye've—
Now that I think of it, I've yet to hear thy name.
But what difference does that make?
Thy past name henceforth has no meaning to thee.
Be that as it may, my servant—
Welcome, to the world of the night.
Wh-
Where am I?
They call it a cram school, though it seems to have gone out of business.
Now it's nothing more than an abandoned building.
Convenient for concealing ourselves as we have been.
Okay, Kiss-shot. My next question is—
Stop!
I said to call me Heart-under-blade!
But that's way too long.
Kiss-shot is shorter and easier to say...
Or am I not supposed to call you that?
Oh well.
If ye be fine with it, then 'tis fine.
I have no reason to deny thee.
And?
What is thy next question?
Um... I've been turned into a vampire, right?
But of course.
There's no need for me to spell it out to thee.
Ye have become my thrall and my servant.
Consider it an honor.
Your servant...
So, why do you look like a child now?
Earlier you were more, uh, mature—
Sorry for not being more "mature"!
No, that's not what I mean.
Mature
And
Your limbs were severed
I wrung thee dry to the last drop.
Yet that was still not nearly enough.
Which is why I've taken on an appropriate form.
'Tis better that dying,
though I'm only able to sustain the bare minimum of immortality.
Most all of my powers as a vampire have been curtailed.
Such an inconvenience.
Flashback
As thou can see, I was able to regenerate my limbs, at least in form.
There's no meat in them...
but they will suffice for the time being.
But let me make our relationship clear for thee, servant.
Though I may have taken on this guise, I am a vampire who has lived through 500 years.
Not to mention our master and servant relationship.
In truth, I am not one to be addressed as an equal by a newly born vampire such as thee.
O-Oh.
What a vague reply.
Do ye understand me?
Well, yeah.
Then as proof of thy submission to me, stroke my head!
That should do.
Why did you turn me into a vampire?
I was ready for you to suck me dry, for you to kill me.
It's not as if it was intentional.
One whose blood is sucked by a vampire is turned into a vampire, without exception.
There was nothing more to it.
Oh. I see.
Well, it's quite convenient for me. Guess why.
It is because there is something thou must do for me.
My body could only recover to this point with thy blood alone.
I am far from my full power.
Going forward, thou must act for me.
What do you want from me?
Can I...
Can I ever become human again?
I thought so.
I was prepared for that question.
So? Can I?!
Sure ye can.
I give thee my assurance.
Upon my name.
The names of the three people who robbed Kiss-shot of parts of her body
Those three specialize in slaying vampires.
They're the ones that killed you?
Don't be a fool,
I haven't been slain yet.
But having my limbs stolen hurts.
I've nearly none of my regenerative powers left,
and in my current state, I can hardly fight. Which is why,
ye shall contend against the three and simply return to me my limbs.
Huh?
S-Simply? As if it will be easy.
In order to turn thee back into a human, I must be at my full power.
In full form, so to speak.
And for that, I absolutely require those limbs.
But me, fight? It's totally not my thing, you know?
Oh, and, wouldn't they just try to slay me, too?
Fool.
That was when ye were human.
You are now my thrall.
Now that I am at my weakest,
it would be simple for thee even to slay me.
So, are you weak for a vampire or what?
Nonsense!
Well, even if I'm stronger than you in your weakened form,
those three were able to take your limbs from you when you were at your full strength, right?
In that case—
I slipped up only because there were three of them.
I'd made light of them.
In short,
faced one at a time,
they pose no problem for thee.
To put it plainly, 'tis an easy job.
Wh-What now?
Dismember
Would you at least hear me out?!
I'm a human, okay?!
Are you gonna murder a human?!
Mur
der
Spin
You three sure are spirited.
Something good happen to you three?
Huh?
Thanks, you saved me.
No need for thanks.
You saved yourself,
Araragi.
Oh, don't be so guarded.
Your eyes are glaring.
So spirited.
Something good happen to you today?
Anyway, Araragi, let's go home for now.
Home?
That abandoned cram school.
Huh?
Hold on a minute,
h-how do you know?
Why wouldn't I?
I was the one who told that girl about the place.
Well, I was merely doing the right thing.
That girl, Heart-under-blade, seemed to be in quite a bit of trouble dragging your body around,
so I told her about a good spot.
Who are you?
I'm just a dude passing by.
Don't worry.
I'm not an expert at slaying vampires or anything.
I practice in a much wider field.
I'll introduce myself properly later.
Ye've returned!
Who is that behind you?
I do seem to recall his face.
I can't believe you.
Is that all I am to you?
So?
How did it go?
What a predicament...
So those three still act as a unit, do they?
They took you out even at your full power.
I stand no chance against them.
Which is why I told you to take them on one by one!
They're together. It's not happening.
You said we'd be fine as long as we laid low,
but there's no telling when they'll find this—
That's not a problem.
I quietly went ahead and placed a barrier here while you two were asleep.
A barrier?
Like a force field?
Well, something like that.
Listen you, what are you planning?
Why are you helping Kiss-shot...
and me?
I'm starting to understand that you're not an enemy,
even though I can't see you as an ally.
What a terrible thing to say.
What I'm trying to do is balance things out.
You could call that my job.
An intermediary—between here and there.
Now introduce yourself.
You said you would.
Spin
Oshino Mèmè.
Oshino Mèmè
A free spirit with no permanent address.
Well, you can just think of me as an authority on yokai and the like.
Though unlike those three, I'm not particularly good at slaying yokai.
Not particularly good?
To be a little more honest,
I don't like it.
But, it's your specialty?
Balancing things is my specialty, like I said.
Standing in between and finding a happy middle ground.
If you had to, you could call me a negotiator.
A negotiator?
An intermediary—between here and there?
Where was "here"—
and where was "there"?
Speech / Voice
Here being humans and there being monsters?
In that case, now I
belong to which side?
Monsters?
I like it.
Though I call them aberrations.
Aberration
And that girl there is known as the aberration slayer.
She's the rare kind of vampire able to drain the energy from aberrations.
And that's why the kid's famous.
I listened to a bit of your exchange earlier.
You two seem to be in a pretty tight spot.
I never would've expected complications.
There isn't a thing complicated about it.
In fact, 'tis quite simple.
Maybe if you looked at it from a vampire's lifespan,
but it spells trouble for humans like us.
Right, Araragi?
And Heart-under-blade, I'm pleased.
You made Araragi your thrall, but you do intend to turn him back into a human.
If you'd like, I don't mind interceding.
Between us and those three?
Who else?
S-So you'll save us?
I'm not going to save you. Just lending you a helping hand.
The balance still seems a little off as things are—
like you're being bullied.
Oh, but of course, this is my job, so I wouldn't do it for free.
Say...
How about 2 million yen?
2 million?!
Akasegawa
You pay when you have it. I won't ever bother you for the money.
But I need to at least charge that much, or else it won't all balance out.
B-But...
Shall we hear your exact plan?
Ye speak of negotiation, but it could not be easy.
There is no way to persuade those three.
All I can do is bow my head and ask them
nicely.
If they don't listen, I'll have to fall back on dangerous ideas.
But if we're lucky and they do,
the game will be on.
The game... ye say?
But the first order of business would be to split up those three.
They pose no problem faced one at a time—isn't that your take on it, Heart-under-blade?
Then we just need to make that happen.
Still, boy, how do ye plan on negotiating with those three?
The details are a trade secret, but...
I'll ready the battleground.
Then Araragi, you will get Heart-under-blade's limbs back from them.
If you recover all four—Heart-under-blade regains her power,
and you go right back to being human.
My servant.
I can't provide human currency—
I'm unsure how much of a debt 2 million yen is,
but is it a sum ye could take on?
Worry not.
The boy's skills are real.
I can tell that much even in my weakened state.
I don't have that kind of money saved up,
but if I can pay you when I have it
and you won't bother me for it,
and if you also don't need any guarantor or collateral...
I'll take it on.
Alright, deal then.
Thanks for your business.
Just kidding.
Voice only
Kiss-shot Acerola-orion Heart-under-blade
Eye for an eye, tooth for a tooth.
Iron-blooded, hot-blooded, yet cold-blooded
Vampire for a vampire.
Red
Unnumbered Scene
Vampire
Voice only
Dramaturgy
Then let us begin.
A massive man over seven feet
tall.
A dual wielder of wavy
greatswords, apparently
known as flamberges.
A mountain of a man—a ball of
pure muscle.
The hairband he wore to hold
back his hair stood out, too.
And—he was vampire hunter
who had taken Kiss-shot's right
leg from her.
(omitted)
The date was March 31st.
The last day of the month.
A massive man over seven feet
tall.
A dual wielder of wavy
greatswords, apparently
known as flamberges.
A mountain of a man—a ball of
pure muscle.
The hairband he wore to hold
back his hair stood out, too.
And—he was vampire hunter
who had taken Kiss-shot's right
leg from her.
(omitted)
The date was March 31st.
The last day of the month.
A kin-slayer vampire
Voice only
Episode
Gotta love it!
A man with sanpaku eyes and a white traditional school uniform who carried
on his shoulder, with one hand, a gigantic cross triple the size and the cube
of the weight of his body.
A man with sanpaku eyes and a white traditional school uniform who carried
on his shoulder, with one hand, a gigantic cross triple the size and the cube
of the weight of his body.
Apparently, he was a vampire hunter. A man who slew vampires in order to collect bounties. A hit man, if you will. And to add to that—
Half vampire
Voice only
Guillotine Cutter
How unpleasant.
The priestly man with the hedgehoggish hair.
Narrow eyes that, on first glance, appeared gentle.
Human
A human who denied the existence of aberrations.
A human who eliminated the existence of aberrations.
Araragi!
Voice only
Hanekawa Tsubasa
You don't need to care about me!
He's a nice guy, but that's not all.
He's strong.
Voice only
How could I not care about you?!
Araragi Koyomi
That was the first time.
If I can't see you ever again,
I felt like I finally met Hanekawa for real.
there's no point in being a human again at all!
No mistakes. Straight, eye to eye.
Araragi.
Preview
Forget about your humanity.
Kizumonogatari
Hot-blooded Chapter
In theaters nationwide summer 2016
Kizumonogatari
Hot-blooded Chapter
In theaters nationwide summer 2016