Gridman Voice Drama: Episode 12.12
The Return of Akane
It's so cold...
It is snowing.
Yeah...
After Shinjou disappeared, the summer weather ended really quick.
Ah, you're right. That said, I heard Hibiki-kun's gonna be okay.
Yeah, I heard he's fully recovered, too.
Seriously? Was it from that thing Gridman did at the end? The whatever-beam?
The Fixer Beam?
Yeah, yeah, that. Surprised you remembered.
Well, I don't know if it was just from that, but I'm just glad that Yuuta's okay.
So his amnesia is...?
Ah, gone. I heard they're still going to run some tests at the hospital, though.
Well, I heard his family would be there with him, so he should be fine.
Hm, I see.
So, I've been meaning to ask you something.
Uh... Rikka-san, what do you think of Yuuta?
Huh...?
Aaaaah hah...
Gridman told you about him. Didn't he? Rikka, don't you remember?
Ah, right... heh.
Don't just give me a "right... heh."
Come on, Utsumi, why does it matter?
No, now quit trying to deflect.
Eeeeh?
Well, are you not going to answer?
I wouldn't do that.
Then how do you feel?
How do I feel, huh...? Hmmm...
Hmmm, wait, wait... eh?
Stop trying to change the subject.
No, seriously! Look! That person on the bridge!
I said, stop trying to—
No way... How is she here?
It's definitely her, right?
It's really her... Shinjou Akane!
She's... back? Akane's back? Let's go talk to her!
Yeah, let's go!
Hey!
Yes?
How... Shinjou-san... why are you here?
Akane...
Eh? Sorry, but...
Huh?
Uh... So... you're not Shinjou Akane?
I'm... not.
Sorry.
It's really not you?
I... believe so.
Oh, come on! You're definitely Shinjou!
You've got such silky hair, you're wearing a loose hoodie, and black tights!
And this area which will go unnamed... it's ginormous!
This miracle of the universe can only be Shinjou Akane!
Are you sure you're not her? You look exactly like her!
Can I please go?
Hold on! Look, look! She even sounds just like her!
You sound just like her!
You have the wrong person!
Oh, then... can you please tell us your name?
Eh...?
Are you hitting on me?
I'm not hitting on you! Look... you said that you're not Shinjou Akane, right?
Then what is your name? If you don't mind telling us...
That's personal information...
Oh, jeez... she's not even gonna tell us her name...
Well, the way you asked her was honestly kinda scary.
That's for sure...
Wait, Rikka-san, why are you taking her side?
I don't think that she's Akane. I mean, she looks exactly like her, but I don't think she's her.
What?
That's what I've been trying to say...
Gimme a sec.
Look at this!
A tokusatsu magazine?
Uh... One sec... here. Look at this page.
Um... What is it?
Look at this kaiju. What's its name? Tell me!
Kaiju?
Yeah, it's a really popular one. What's it called? Red? Red what? It's a red kaiju!
Heh. Looks like an ear of corn.
It's not an ear of corn! It's Red King!
I don't know what that is! What do you want from me?
Rikka-san.
Yes?
This person... is not Shinjou Akane.
Why did you say it like that?
If she really were Shinjou Akane, she'd definitely know Red King! Especially the 3rd one!
I like the 3rd one!
Huh? Wait, so you are—
Um, my ex-boyfriend use to pick this song at karaoke. And I actually ended up liking it!
We're not talking about the J Soul Brothers!
Well, you said "the 3rd!"
No, no... and we didn't need to know about your ex either!
Sorry... he was actually my 2nd ex.
You're saying too much!
You're pretty popular, huh?
Eh, I'm not that popular...
A popular person would say that.
Look how cute she is, it's not weird she'd have a boyfriend, right?
Sure, but you can't just start talking about your exes... guys don't really appreciate that!
Is that so?
You don't understand guys at all.
Um, why is he talking like he's the representative of all males on Earth?
Don't worry about him, he's always like this.
Aaah! I got it!
Whoa, quiet down, you scared me.
I figured it out! Yes, yes, it makes total sense.
You're the person that Shinjou Akane is based on. I've seen this a few times before. Yep, yep.
What are you talking about?
It's like, when Shinjou Akane came to this world, she copied this person.
I'm really sorry for taking up your time like this.
Um, it's okay...
Listen to me!
So you're a different person after all. You're not Shinjou Akane.
That's what I've been trying to say.
So can I go now?
Yeah... sorry about all of this.
Ah, you don't need to apologize.
So are you looking for this Shinjou-san?
Well, how should I put it...?
Well, he really liked her,
and she...
moved away.
Oh, I see. That's so sad...
That's... not true. I didn't, um... L-L-Like her. That much. To be honest.
Utsumi-kun, come on. You're not in middle school anymore.
H-H-Huh?
Hah! You're blushing so hard! That's so cute!
I'm not blushing!
Oh really, huh? Are you sure you didn't like her?
You... didn't like her?
I... Um... Well... I did like her. Fine.
Oh wow! Your voice sounded so creepy!
You're the one who made me do it!
He's blushing!
I'm not blushing!
Just go "I'm not blushing! I'm Red King!"
Shut up! You think you're clever?! You're not!
Wait, wait... Did he just touch you?
Huh? Eh?
Can you please not touch me?
I w-w-wasn't—
We found a molester.
Excuse me! I've been molested!
Oh, come on!
Let's get outta here, he's gonna grab your boobs.
What are you doing?
Oh my god! That's scary!
I'm not gonna do that!
Run away!
Wait!
I'm not going to do that! I'm not—
Even though... I want to...
My belly hurts from laughing so much!
Me too!
Who was that guy? Your friend?
Eh, I guess. We're in the same class.
By the way, can you tell me your name? My name's Rikka. Takarada Rikka.
Rikka? My name is—
Our laughter echoed over Tsutsujidai.
Our breath was white.
The snow on our cheeks melted in an instant.
We would never be alone.
No matter when...
No matter where...