Wait your turn.
I'm sorry. I don't have any more.
So pretty...
Like a lake mirroring the blue sky.
Whoa, what is this?
It's super blue.
So pretty...
Here.
You can have it.
Huh?
Don't want it?
Thank you?
Why the questioning tone?
You're very welcome?
Let's go.
I'm happy.
Oh, you're happy about it too, Mizore?
Same here.
This piece is great.
I'm really happy we picked it for our free-choice piece.
Yep.
Did you know about it before?
Nope.
It's composed by Uda-san,
who's really popular at competitions lately.
Isn't she great?
I don't know her.
That so?
Yep.
Liz and the
Blue Bird
I borrowed this from the library.
Liz and the
Blue Bird
I read this way back when I was a little girl.
You?
It's the story of this lonesome girl called Liz.
Lonesome?
Liz had been living all alone for ages,
but one day, a mysterious girl comes to her.
Hey, you.
What's your name?
I'm Kasaki Nozomi.
Wanna join the concert band with me?
The two of them hit it off and start living together,
but they part in the end.
The girl who appeared before Liz was actually a blue bird,
and she flies off, leaving Liz behind.
I think that's how the story goes.
They're kinda like us, don't you think?
How do you m—
But it's so sad that they have to part.
I like stories with happy endings better.
Yep.
Wanna try playing the part with the solo?
Third Movement.
Liz and the Blue Bird
"Mundane Days"
"New Family"
"A Decision Born of Love"
"To a Distant Sky"
Liz and the Blue Bird
Composer: Uda Yuriko
First Movement
Second Movement
Third Movement
Fourth Movement
"Mundane Days"
"New Family"
"A Decision Born of Love"
"To a Distant Sky"
Liz and the Blue Bird
Composer: Uda Yuriko
First Movement
Second Movement
Third Movement
Fourth Movement
"Mundane Days"
"New Family"
"A Decision Born of Love"
"To a Distant Sky"
Liz and the Blue Bird
Composer: Uda Yuriko
First Movement
Second Movement
Third Movement
Fourth Movement
"Mundane Days"
"New Family"
"A Decision Born of Love"
"To a Distant Sky"
Liz and the Blue Bird
Composer: Uda Yuriko
First Movement
Second Movement
Third Movement
Fourth Movement
"Mundane Days"
"New Family"
"A Decision Born of Love"
"To a Distant Sky"
Liz and the Blue Bird
Composer: Uda Yuriko
First Movement
Second Movement
Third Movement
Fourth Movement
"Mundane Days"
"New Family"
"A Decision Born of Love"
"To a Distant Sky"
Liz and the Blue Bird
Composer: Uda Yuriko
First Movement
Second Movement
Third Movement
Fourth Movement
"Mundane Days"
"New Family"
"A Decision Born of Love"
"To a Distant Sky"
Liz and the Blue Bird
Composer: Uda Yuriko
First Movement
Second Movement
Third Movement
Fourth Movement
"Mundane Days"
"New Family"
"A Decision Born of Love"
"To a Distant Sky"
Liz and the Blue Bird
Composer: Uda Yuriko
First Movement
Second Movement
Third Movement
Fourth Movement
"Mundane Days"
"New Family"
"A Decision Born of Love"
"To a Distant Sky"
Liz and the Blue Bird
Composer: Uda Yuriko
First Movement
Second Movement
Third Movement
Fourth Movement
"Mundane Days"
"New Family"
"A Decision Born of Love"
"To a Distant Sky"
Second Movement
Third Movement
Fourth Movement
"Mundane Days"
"New Family"
"A Decision Born of Love"
"To a Distant Sky"
Second Movement
Third Movement
Fourth Movement
"Mundane Days"
"New Family"
"A Decision Born of Love"
"To a Distant Sky"
Second Movement
Third Movement
Fourth Movement
"Mundane Days"
"New Family"
"A Decision Born of Love"
"To a Distant Sky"
Second Movement
Third Movement
Fourth Movement
"Mundane Days"
"New Family"
"A Decision Born of Love"
"To a Distant Sky"
Second Movement
Third Movement
Fourth Movement
"Mundane Days"
"New Family"
"A Decision Born of Love"
"To a Distant Sky"
Second Movement
Third Movement
Fourth Movement
"Mundane Days"
"New Family"
"A Decision Born of Love"
"To a Distant Sky"
Second Movement
Third Movement
Fourth Movement
"Mundane Days"
"New Family"
"A Decision Born of Love"
"To a Distant Sky"
Second Movement
Third Movement
Fourth Movement
"Mundane Days"
"New Family"
"A Decision Born of Love"
"To a Distant Sky"
Liz and the Blue Bird
Composer: Uda Yuriko
First Movement
Second Movement
Third Movement
Fourth Movement
"Mundane Days"
"New Family"
"A Decision Born of Love"
"To a Distant Sky"
Liz and the Blue Bird
Composer: Uda Yuriko
First Movement
Second Movement
Third Movement
Fourth Movement
"Mundane Days"
"New Family"
"A Decision Born of Love"
"To a Distant Sky"
Liz and the Blue Bird
Composer: Uda Yuriko
First Movement
Second Movement
Third Movement
Fourth Movement
"Mundane Days"
"New Family"
"A Decision Born of Love"
"To a Distant Sky"
Liz and the Blue Bird
Composer: Uda Yuriko
First Movement
Second Movement
Third Movement
Fourth Movement
"Mundane Days"
"New Family"
"A Decision Born of Love"
"To a Distant Sky"
Liz and the Blue Bird
Composer: Uda Yuriko
First Movement
Second Movement
Third Movement
Fourth Movement
"Mundane Days"
"New Family"
"A Decision Born of Love"
"To a Distant Sky"
Liz and the Blue Bird
Composer: Uda Yuriko
First Movement
Second Movement
Third Movement
Fourth Movement
"Mundane Days"
"New Family"
"A Decision Born of Love"
"To a Distant Sky"
Liz and the Blue Bird
Composer: Uda Yuriko
First Movement
Second Movement
Third Movement
Fourth Movement
"Mundane Days"
"New Family"
"A Decision Born of Love"
"To a Distant Sky"
Liz and the Blue Bird
Composer: Uda Yuriko
First Movement
Second Movement
Third Movement
Fourth Movement
"Mundane Days"
"New Family"
"A Decision Born of Love"
"To a Distant Sky"
Liz and the Blue Bird
Composer: Uda Yuriko
First Movement
Second Movement
Third Movement
Fourth Movement
"Mundane Days"
"New Family"
"A Decision Born of Love"
"To a Distant Sky"
Liz and the Blue Bird
Composer: Uda Yuriko
First Movement
Second Movement
Third Movement
Fourth Movement
"Mundane Days"
"New Family"
"A Decision Born of Love"
"To a Distant Sky"
Liz and the Blue Bird
Composer: Uda Yuriko
First Movement
Second Movement
Third Movement
Fourth Movement
"Mundane Days"
"New Family"
"A Decision Born of Love"
"To a Distant Sky"
Liz and the Blue Bird
Composer: Uda Yuriko
First Movement
Second Movement
Third Movement
Fourth Movement
"Mundane Days"
"New Family"
"A Decision Born of Love"
"To a Distant Sky"
Liz and the Blue Bird
Composer: Uda Yuriko
First Movement
Second Movement
Third Movement
Fourth Movement
"Mundane Days"
"New Family"
"A Decision Born of Love"
"To a Distant Sky"
Liz and the Blue Bird
Composer: Uda Yuriko
First Movement
Second Movement
Third Movement
"Mundane Days"
"New Family"
"A Decision Born of Love"
Fourth Movement
"To a Distant Sky"
"A Decision Born of Love"?
The beginning.
Ready.
Liz and the Blue Bird
Was the pitch kinda off?
Well.
I guess we have lots of time.
I can't wait for the day we play this on stage.
Nozomi.
Do you like practicing?
I do.
I like it a lot.
And this piece?
I love it.
I mean...
I can't wait for the day.
Morning.
Awfully early for a Sunday, aren't we?
I'm impressed.
Morning!
Oh, Prez.
Good morning.
You clearly saw me, didn't you?
I'm not fully awake yet.
They're at it again.
Good morning.
Oh, morning.
You're here really early.
You girls are plenty early too.
I suppose we are.
Nozomi-senpai!
Good morning!
Oh, you're here already?
We are.
See you after sectional.
'Kay.
Liz and the
Blue Bird
Want some gummies, Senpai?
Oh, I'll have some.
Hey! I was asking Senpai!
C'mon, I skipped breakfast.
Don't do that. You'll run out of steam.
What's your breakfast like?
Just toast.
With cheese or eggs or stuff.
Rice and whatever.
Rice mixed with miso soup.
That's illegal.
Hey, it's good.
Illegal.
And Tsubomi?
Uh...
French toast.
I can't wait for the day we play this on stage.
I hope that day never comes.
Hey.
Good day.
Good morning, Arlt.
Morning, Liz.
Thank you very much.
See you tomorrow.
Liz.
We're closing up for today.
See you tomorrow.
Thank you.
See you tomorrow, Arlt.
Make us prepared for eternity.
It's morning.
Has the storm passed?
I hope everyone's all right.
So bright!
As though there was never a storm!
Blue...
A girl?
Oh no!
Hey, what's the matter?
Are you all right?
Liz?
Liz!
That's enough.
That'll do for today's practice.
We worked on our required repertoire today,
but the plan is to focus on Liz tomorrow.
Make sure you all come prepared.
Yes, sir!
Would you like to say anything, President?
Sure.
As decided by vote,
our goal this year is to win gold at Nationals.
We'll be holding auditions soon,
but whether you're chosen to compete or not,
we're all still part of the same team.
Let's work together and present the best Kitauji has to offer.
Right!
That's all I have to say.
Hey, that's pretty cute.
It really is cute!
Your cloth is pretty cute too, Nozo-senpai.
Nozo-senpai? That's cute.
Too cute! Nozo-senpai!
Just how important is cute to you girls?
All important!
You're in perfect sync.
Pop.
Good work today.
The flutes are always so full of life.
They're like a group of birds chirping.
As if.
Senpai?
The bassoonists and I are having a double-reed party soon.
Well, we'll just be stopping for tea on the way home.
Would you like to join us, Yoroizuka-senpai?
Us four double-reeders should stick together.
I'm good.
Is... that so?
See you.
Nozomi.
Oh, good work, Mizore.
I'm hitting up a family restaurant with the flute girls today.
Is that so?
Yeah.
'Kay.
Bye.
Yeah. See you tomorrow.
See you tomorrow.
The book from this morning.
Right. Sorry about that.
Thanks.
Nozomi, do you like that story?
I do, though the ending is a little sad.
Nozo-senpai!
Coming!
Later.
'Kay.
More like Double-ble Reed!
Right?
Goodbye, Yoroizuka-senpai.
Goodbye.
Bye.
She's so cold.
Great work.
Uh...
Wait!
Uh, aren't you the oboe girl...
Yoroi—wait, no. I'm Kenzaki.
Right...
So, what is it?
I need some advice regarding Yoroino—wait, no, Yoroizuka-senpai.
Mizore?
What's up?
Um, you two are close, right?
I sure hope so.
Right?
So I'd like some advice from you.
Yeah, what is it?
Right.
Well...
I don't think... she likes me very much.
Really?
Why?
You see...
Library
When I talk to her, she doesn't respond much.
Even when we do have a conversation, it's like she doesn't care at all.
It's making me think that maybe I've gotten on her bad side.
Well, Mizore can be a bit of a mystery at times.
I think you, uh...
Kenzaki.
Also, Ririka.
I don't think she hates you or anything, Ririka-chan.
Really?
Yeah. Don't worry.
Thank you very much...
Oh.
Here, as thanks.
The heck is this?
A boiled egg from the convenience store.
It's flavored and very yummy.
Huh...
Goodbye.
Liz.
Here.
Is it good?
Yep!
Help!
I'm glad you're all better now.
Liz's handkerchief.
I didn't know there were so many types of bread, Liz!
Now you do.
Is it okay if I pick too?
Sure.
Want to try it?
Yum!
It's yummy!
Say, where did you come from?
I don't know.
I saw many forests and towns.
Why did you come here?
Because you were alone, Liz.
I wanted to play with you lots.
Wait!
What's wrong?
Please...
Be with me!
Forever and ever!
"Be with me."
The gates will close soon.
Please leave at once.
Um.
Do you mind? I need to lock up.
Morning.
Morning!
Did your homework?
I love you!
You're a hard worker,
super cool, and great at sports! Everything about you is cool!
Satsuki, I...
I Love You,
the hug.
Are those two from Minami Middle?
That was all the rage when we were there.
Yep.
We sure did that a lot.
We'd hug and say what we loved about each other.
I only watched. I never did it.
Never?
Then...
Just kidding. Did you not wanna?
Sorry about that.
N-No.
Let's go.
See ya.
Yep.
Heya.
Mizore.
Yay.
Natsuki.
Come on.
Yoroizuka.
Your career plans survey.
It had nothing but your name on it.
Fill it out and turn it in by next week.
Yes, sir.
Let's take 2 and 3, or 4 and 5.
When two integers have a greatest common divisor of 1,
Yoroizuka Mizore
Career Plans Survey
Class 3-1
they are said to be relatively prime or co-prime.
Natsuki!
Gah...
Okay, switch out.
Mizore.
Time to switch.
Yep.
Not going?
Uh... fine.
Hup.
I'll join!
He said I was cute!
It was a classmate, a boy in Life Sciences.
Cool. How'd it go down?
We were talking about what our usual breakfast was like.
"French toast"...
...is what she said, apparently.
Hey, you ripped that off.
That's Tsubomi's deal.
She's blushing.
Have you ever gone on a date, Nozo-senpai?
Huh?!
Yoroizuka Mizore
Career Plans Survey
Class 3-1
Blowfish.
Auditions soon.
Yeah.
The flute solo will probably go to Nozo-senpai, huh?
Yeah. She's so good.
Play the
solo!
Look, Liz.
The moon's back!
It's so pretty.
Tomorrow will be a fine day too.
It will.
Another day full of playing with Liz!
I love you, Liz.
I love you too.
Good night. See you tomorrow.
See you tomorrow.
It'll get chilly soon.
Yes. Winter is coming.
Where will you go when it arrives?
Nowhere.
I'll be right here.
Really?
Wait your turn.
That tickles!
Good boy.
Yoroizuka-san.
Niiyama-sensei?
May I speak with you?
It's been a while.
How did you know I was here?
Yoroi—wait, no, Kenzaki-san said you might be here.
I see.
You've picked a wonderful piece for the competition.
In this piece, the flute and oboe are said to represent Liz and the blue bird.
The dueling solos in the Third Movement must symbolize Liz and the girl's parting.
Nozomi? She quit yesterday.
Huh? You didn't know, Yoroizuka-san?
Dunno.
I don't really understand why Liz lets the blue bird go.
You don't?
Oh, right. I came to discuss something with you.
Yoroizuka-san,
have you decided on your career plans yet?
Nice.
Yeah.
Mizore?
Mizore.
What were you up to?
Feeding the blowfish.
Huh.
Like Liz?
Yep.
Are you into blowfish now?
Yep. They're cute.
Can I go with you sometime?
Yeah.
Feed them with me.
What's that?
This? A brochure.
Yeah, that I can tell.
Can I see?
Yep.
A music school brochure?
Wow.
Wait a second.
Are you going to music school?
Niiyama-sensei gave it to me and asked if I was interested.
Nozomi?
Maybe I should apply here.
Then I will too.
If you're applying, I will too.
What kind of scheduling is that?
You're taking too much upon yourself.
Mind your own business.
You're not Asuka-senpai.
I know that.
Oh, right.
Nozomi, how are the funds looking?
Tsukamoto, Takigawa, and Takino are yet to pay.
Get them to at once.
I have to do it?
Aren't you the treasurer?
Oh, I've got a mock exam this day.
Sucks. I want to focus on band.
You're applying to the same college as me.
You sure have an adorable side, huh?
Huh? That's the thing I hate most about this.
We'll always be best friends, even in college.
Yikes. Am I getting goosebumps here?
The same college thing was a total coincidence, okay?
Okay, okay.
Mizore's going to music school.
Really? That's great, Mizore.
Right?
Nozomi's applying,
so I am too.
Why are you two taking it seriously?
She's just joking.
You're applying to music school?
Hmm...
I guess.
It's not set in stone, though.
Oh, right.
Hey—
The Agata Festival's almost here.
Crap. There's just not enough time.
It'd do you good to take your mind off band for a bit.
Mizore, let's go together.
To the Agata Festival.
Huh? Do you have plans?
Nope.
Let's go, then.
If you want to.
Yuuko, Natsuki, you're both free too, right?
Yeah. Okay, I'll go.
And Prez?
Yeah, I'll go.
Grr.
Do you wanna invite anyone else, Mizore?
Wow, you look really dumb right now.
Again, mind your own business.
Nope.
That so?
Nozo-senpai. I'm going to the aquarium soon!
With that boy from class?
Way to go!
What will you wear?
Gotta be a one-piece dress!
You don't have one, do you? A one-piece?
I don't.
Wanna borrow mine?
What? Can I really?!
Thank you, Tsubo-senpai!
Can you even fit into Tsubomi's clothes?
Mizo-senpai.
Look at that rain.
Oh, can I not call you Mizo-senpai?
No... you can.
Yay.
Mizo-senpai, this is pretty.
Where'd you get it? They only sell white ones.
Lucky you.
Nozomi gave it to me.
You two really are close.
Lucky.
Mizo-senpai.
We're having another double-reed party before auditions.
If you don't mind, could you maybe, possibly join us?
I wouldn't be any fun if I went.
That's not true!
Some other time.
'Kay...
Library
Uh...
Liz and the Blue Bird
The return date was a month ago.
I'm pretty sure there were other people who wanted to borrow it.
The library's books belong to every student.
Yes, yes, we get it!
We'll keep that in mind.
Let's go.
She didn't have to be such a nag.
Yep.
It's really easy to forget to return a book, huh?
If you just wanted to read Liz, I would've
lent you the one I borrowed.
That's not allowed.
That'd be a sub-lend.
What's gotten into you?
You can't lend a library book to anyone else—
Yes, yes, I get it!
Mizo-senpai.
Do you make your own reeds?
Half of them, I guess?
So you just scrape?
I also string them up.
Eh?
Do you think I could do it too?
I can teach you sometime.
You mean it?
Yep.
Wow, I'm so happy.
Thank you so much.
What's wrong?
I failed the audition!
I wanted to perform on stage with you!
Happy Ice Cream!
What the heck?
Huh? You don't know?
You and I said the same thing just now, didn't we?
Yeah, we did.
I'm hungry.
I want to eat something sweet.
I wanna eat something sweet.
When that happens, you immediately say "Happy Ice Cream."
Okay.
Whoever says it first gets the other to buy them ice cream.
Wait, what? Does that mean I have to buy you ice cream now?
Exactly.
Thanks for the treat, Hazuki-chan.
Huh?
What the heck? I'd never heard of this before!
Mizore.
Can I put the chairs here?
Yep.
Down you go.
Summer's here!
I really wanna take a dip now!
Hey, Mizore.
Do you have plans for the upcoming break?
Nothing in particular.
Really? Let's hit the pool, then!
I'll go.
Great.
We have a plan.
Hey, Nozomi.
Can I invite someone?
What do we have here?
You'd normally never say something like that.
Sure. Who is it?
Sneak...
Ta-da!
Pic from the pool.
Boy, I was so nervous. There were so many upperclassmen there.
Oh, but,
I was really happy that you invited me.
I have a precious summer memory now.
Yep.
Oh, can I send you the pic?
'Kay.
I'll do my best to compete next year.
Mizo-senpai
Thank you very much!
Love you, Senpai!
Mizo-senpai
Thank you very much!
Love you, Senpai!
Mizo-senpai
'Kay.
Can you check my reed?
Kasaki-san, are you listening to the oboe?
You're not doing badly,
but your playing is a little bit too emotional.
In this section, what matters most is listening to the other's notes.
You must whisper softly to Yoroizuka-san, not overwhelm her.
Can you do that for me?
Yes, sir.
Yoroizuka-san.
You have to remember that this is
a back-and-forth between the oboe and flute.
It can't be one-sided. You must respond to the flute's questions.
Music sometimes has aspects that cannot be fully expressed in a score.
Please learn to read between the lines of the sheet music.
And sing your heart out.
Can you do that for me?
Yes, sir.
Scraping a reed?
Yep. For Ririka-chan.
I see.
You're applying to a music school, right?
Yep.
Does that make you happy, Yuuko?
Of course. I'm really glad.
I know you'll get in.
I'm glad.
Say, Mizore.
Are you applying to a music school
only because Nozomi is?
Is that weird?
Nah.
Are you okay?
Nozomi's decision is my decision.
I see.
Yuuko-senpai.
The trumpeters have gathered.
Oh, okay. I'll be right there.
What's up?
Um, may I?
I'm sorry.
I've been wondering about the oboe solo for the free-choice piece.
Senpai,
aren't you incompatible with Nozomi-senpai?
Kousaka?
That's not true.
I don't know. Your notes right now
sounded really trapped to me.
It's like you're chaining them down on purpose.
Probably because you don't think Nozomi-senpai can keep up with you.
Kousaka!
No.
I'm sorry.
It's not like I wanted to put you on the spot.
But,
I want to hear you play with everything you have.
Excuse me.
Jeez...
You okay, Mizore?
You're wrong. It's not Nozomi's fault.
They sound trapped because I can't let go of the blue bird.
I mean, I don't know when Nozomi will leave me again.
I can't push her away.
Not with my own hands.
I can never release her myself.
There's just no way.
If I were Liz,
I'd keep the blue bird caged forever.
Natsuki, you taking mock exams?
I am. At least three.
Oh?
And Mizore?
One.
Wait, she didn't tell you?
Nah.
Even though you're applying to the same college?
I know, right?
Has Mizore said anything?
About what?
About... you know?
Nothing really.
Oh, but she's working hard now that she has a plan in place.
Same college as you and all.
Don't you think she's being kinda distant with me?
How so? You know that's not true.
I quit band in first-year, remember?
It feels like the distant past now,
but do you think she still holds a grudge over that, maybe?
She never speaks her mind clearly, you know?
I just can't tell.
We're not agreeing during the solos, too.
If you ask me,
you two come across as the flute and oboe aces. Very cool.
You think?
So, like, the blue bird that Liz sets free?
I think she should just come back when she wants to see her again.
What? That'd waste all of Liz's resolve.
I guess.
But, it's a happy ending, y'know?
Back to help us prepare for this year's competition
are Hashimoto-sensei and Niiyama-sensei,
who'll also oversee practice for a while.
Long time no see, second- and third-years.
And for the first-years, nice to meet you. I'm Hashimoto.
I'll be watching your practice for a while.
Let's do this.
Mizore.
Wanna practice the solo part some more later?
'Kay.
Niiyama-sensei.
Oh.
It's been too long.
Kasaki-san, right?
Thanks for teaching the woodwinds again this year.
You made it onto the competition band this year, huh?
Let's do our best.
Yes, ma'am.
I'm thinking of applying to music school.
Oh, really?
Good luck.
Feel free to ask me for advice.
I will.
See you.
Man, I've been thinking since I listened in that one time...
Uh...
Is the oboe and flute back-and-forth gonna be okay?
So they went to see some kind of blowfish.
And?
He said, "I wanted to show you this fish."
He said it looked just like me!
Isn't that fish cute?
But it's a blowfish!
Doesn't matter as long as it's cute.
Right, Nozomi?
Oh, yeah.
Maybe he was implying I'm fat!
I really couldn't fit into Tsubo-senpai's dress.
Calm down. You're plenty cute as you are.
Nozomi.
Oh, Mizore.
Good work.
Later.
Nozomi.
Are you mad about something?
Not at all.
Will you do it, then?
Some other time.
Urgent!
Collecting Sunfest Scores!
What are you going to do about the Third Movement?
You need to be in perfect sync with Mizore.
Yeah, you're right.
Is it not going well?
What do you mean?
With Mizore.
It's not like that.
Well, there's still time.
We'll figure something out.
Oh, it's Oumae-chan and Kousaka-chan.
That's Nozomi and Mizore's part.
What are they doing?
That was a pretty confident Liz.
Like she was saying, "Take care, then!"
How very Kousaka.
They're having fun.
Say...
Do I really want to go to music school?
Um, I still don't really get the solo.
What are you expressing with your solo?
Liz's feelings.
What are they?
She lets her friend, the blue bird, out of the cage
and sets her free.
That's what she does.
Not how she feels.
Her feelings...
I just don't know.
I could never push away someone I love.
I can't begin to understand them.
I love the flute,
but I'm not sure I wanna go pro.
There's a difference between wanting to play and making it your job.
Also, it'll cost a lot of money, right?
I'd have to take private lessons.
I'm starting to think maybe I should go to a normal college like you two.
Does...
Does Mizore know?
She doesn't.
Why?
"Why," you ask?
You promise to go to the same college together
and then turn around and break it because you don't want to go pro?
Yuuko.
Even back in first-year,
you quit the band without telling her.
And then you came back because you wanted in again.
How many times will you toy with Mizore?
Yuuko.
Being close doesn't mean you have to reveal everything to each other.
Yoroizuka-san,
you hold the people you love too close to your heart.
Well...
Look at it this way.
What if you were the blue bird?
That day, Liz suddenly tells her that they must part,
even though they were living happily together until then.
You should be free.
Your graceful wings can take you as high and as far as you want to go.
But why? I want to be with you forever!
Being with you is the only thing that brings me joy!
I'm nothing but a cage that confines you.
But you have flight.
You have an endless sky to explore.
I cannot take your wings from you.
Now, leave this place and soar far and high into the skies!
Please let me see your beautiful form take flight.
This is how I show my love.
I love you.
Well? Do you think the blue bird could take flight?
She accepts it because Liz said so.
The blue bird can't reject the choice Liz made.
Because the blue bird loves Liz very much.
She has to fly away, even if it breaks her heart.
Was the blue bird unhappy?
I don't know.
But she wants Liz to be happy.
That feeling alone will always stay true.
That's how the blue bird shows her love.
She has to take flight.
Mizore's not the only one who submitted a blank career plans survey.
I did too.
But, you know,
Mizore was the only one Niiyama-sensei talked to.
I've been trying to see myself as Liz the entire time.
I've always thought Liz and the blue bird
were kinda like Mizore and me.
Mizore was...
...Liz,
and Nozomi was...
...the blue bird.
But now...
I sealed her beautiful wings away in all my love for her.
The wings that could take her wherever she wanted.
Oh God, why...
...did you teach me how to open the cage?
Let's begin the all-hands rehearsals, then.
To start—
Excuse me.
Can we do the Third Movement in one go?
Very well.
That was amazing, Senpai.
You took my breath away.
I couldn't focus on my playing.
That was truly incredible, Mizore.
Nozomi?
Nozomi.
Mizore?
Nozomi?
Were you crying?
Nah.
Are you okay?
Mizore...
You were holding back all this while, huh?
You never went all-out because you were lowering yourself to my level.
No—
I'm such a fool...
Telling you to do your best,
when my lack of skill was the very reason you couldn't.
No—
You were the only one Niiyama-sensei suggested music school to.
I guess I should've known.
You've always been so good.
You play dirty, Mizore.
No fair.
Nozomi—
I didn't want you leaving me in the dust.
That's why I said I'd go to the same music school,
thinking that would make us equals.
I'm not that talented, you see.
I'm not amazing like you.
I figured that maybe I could seem your equal if I talked about going to music school.
Nozomi.
I...
I'm not amazing like you.
I'm just an ordinary girl.
No—
You'll probably make your mark on the wider world very soon.
For Liz and the Blue Bird, I'll try not to ruin your performance.
Nozomi...
I'll try to back up your solo—
Will you listen to me?!
You're always so inconsiderate.
You went and quit without telling me back in first-year, too.
Hey, that's in the past now.
No, it's not.
It always remained part of my here and now.
I've always been chasing after you.
I kept playing the oboe because I didn't want you casting me aside.
You've always been my number one.
I've only given the oboe my all because I want to be with you.
As long as I can be with you, I don't care about anything else.
Oh, please. You're exaggerating.
I'm not.
It's all true.
You're no fair.
You're my everything.
I'm not the kind of girl you think I am.
If anything, I deserve your disdain.
You're special to me.
Even the things about you that you think nothing of are all special to me!
Why are you being so nice? I don't—
What's the matter?
I Love You Hug.
If it wasn't for you, I'd have nothing.
I wouldn't be playing an instrument.
When you talked to me,
became my friend, and acted so nice towards me,
it made me really happy.
Sorry, I don't remember that too well.
I think it's amazing how you can lead everyone and enjoy yourself all the time.
You're an amazingly hard worker.
I love the way you laugh.
I love the way you talk.
I love your footsteps.
I love your hair.
I...
I love everything about—
I love your oboe.
Nozomi?
Thanks.
Thank you, Mizore.
Thank you.
Okay, we'd better get going.
Let me go grab my stuff.
So you're Yoroizuka-san?
Are you in any clubs?
You're going straight home, then? You haven't joined any?
Wanna join the concert band, then?
Um...
Liz and the Blue Bird
I'd really like you to stick to the deadline next time.
The library's books belong to every student.
Okay.
Yes, yes, we get it!
I'll take this.
College Entrances
Reference Book
Liz and the Blue Bird
The return date will be one week from today.
Got it.
Take Flight!
Hey, Mizore.
Wanna stop by somewhere on the way home?
Sure.
What do you wanna eat?
Shaved ice.
Nice!
Parfait sounds good too.
Pancakes.
Oh, very nice.
Or we could go classical with dango.
Nozomi.
Thank you?
Why the questioning tone?
Mizore, I...
I'll back up your solo perfectly.
Just give me a little time.
Me too.
I'll keep playing the oboe too.
Great.
Let's do our best on stage!
Happy Ice Cream!
What? You wanna get ice cream?
Let's go with that, then.
ことり
kotori
ひびいたくつのおとを
hibii takutsu no otowo
そっと　とじこめた
sotto toji kometa
やわらかい　ひかり　ふわり
yawa rakai hikari fuwari
やがて　おどりだす　 しょうじょ
yagate odoridasu shoujo
きみのこえ　ひびかせて
kimi no koe hibika sete
どうか　つつませて
douka tsu tsu masete
つまさきで　くるり　まう
tsuma sakide kururi mau
きざまれる　きおく
kiza mareru kioku
いま　わたしの　からだに
ima watashi no karadani
そのこどうを　うつして
sono kodouwo utsu shite
このままこのばしょで
kono mama kono basho de
あいのねをならしていよう
aino ne wo na rashite iyou
The two lines
come close and then get away.
Some easy tricks on Cat's Cradle,
That I can't do so well any more.
On a musical stave,
Seasons pass so fast.
Each spring time,
We're floating there like balloons.
The ghosts
banished from my diary,
Which I burnt in early summer.
A rustling sound in the corridor,
Somewhere in my heart.
Through the frosted window,
If I was aware of the eyes behind the lens.
How would I sing?
Golden reflections of our life,
In the afternoon sunlight.
Chocolates melting in my pocket.
By making it a song,
Can I keep the memory?
I just came to love it now.
By making it a song,
Can I keep the memory?
I just came to love it now.