Mya-nee! Good morning!
Mya-nee, are you awake?
M-Morning...
Good morning!
I'm going now!
Bye...
Miyako! How long are you going to stay in bed?
I'm up! I'm up already...
French toast!
French toast I put in to soak last night!
It was delicious
Mom
Mom...
It was delicious
Mom
Hinata
It was delicious
Mom
Hinata
It was delicious
Mom
Hinata
It was delicious
Mom
Hinata
It was delicious
Mom
Hinata
It was delicious
For Mya-nee !
Hinata
It was delicious
For Mya-nee !
Hinata
It was delicious
For Mya-nee !
Hinata
It was delicious
For Mya-nee !
Hinata
It was delicious
For Mya-nee !
Hinata
It was delicious
For Mya-nee !
Hinata
It was delicious
For Mya-nee !
Hinata
It was delicious
For Mya-nee !
Hinata
Hinata!
Thank you!
Time to eat.
Too sweet!
Hinata's grown some more lately.
I guess I should take her measurements again.
Mya-nee, I'm home!
Is it that time already?
This is my house.
Come in!
Welcome home, Hinata.
Mya-nee, I'm home!
Thank you for having me.
At the end of May,
just when it felt like spring was beginning to wane...
An angel...
flew down to me!
Episode 1: A Funny, Squirmy Feeling
Thank you for having me.
Who is this girl?
She's so cute!
And my face feels hot.
Did I catch a cold or something?
But it wouldn't hit me so suddenly...
Mya-nee!
I brought home a friend today!
This is my big sister, Mya-nee.
She's super shy, so when she first meets people, she can't look them in the eye.
Really...
Um... Pleased to meet you.
I'm Shirosaki Hana.
Oh, um, I...
I-I'm Hoshino... Miyako.
Wow, you responded!
That's amazing, Mya-nee!
Nice job!
You're bright red.
Wha—D-Don't... P-Please don't...
No matter the circumstances, it's not right that my heart is racing like this.
My room's this way.
What is this?
This funny, squirmy feeling I have right here.
For now, I need to calm down.
Just calm down.
Okay, I'm starting to feel calmer.
Let's think logically about how things got this way.
So, when I look at Hana-chan...
I feel funny.
What is this?!
Ugh... What is going on?!
I got even more nervous than usual with Hana-chan.
She's Hinata's friend, so I want to try to get along, but...
Hana-chan...
I just know this sort of thing would look good on Hana-chan!
I hope I can be her friend, too.
But I don't know if I can manage to talk to her face-to-face.
Oh! That's it! I just won't talk face-to-face!
Mya-nee, is that you?
What is it, Mya-nee?
Mya-nee! Mya-nee, save me!
Mya-nee! Where are you?
Isn't that her collapsed right there?
Oh, it is!
Don't scare me like that, Mya-nee.
Sorry...
Uh... Why am I here again?
That's right! I wanted to make friends with Hana-chan.
H-Hana-chan!
Will you... be my friend?
No.
I don't want to.
C-Come on, please?
There's no reason for me to become your friend.
There is a reason, Hana!
Mya-nee has no friends!
It's very sad!
Hinata, don't!
What? Is that true?
No! It's not! I have friends!
I see.
No, really! I have lots!
So... many...
Why don't we be friends, then?
Please don't pity me!
Isn't that great, Mya-nee?
Somehow, this isn't how I pictured things.
Onee-san...
Please don't be sad.
Okay.
What are you doing?
Hana-chan, your hand feels so nice and soft.
That's creepy!
W-Wait! I didn't mean it like that!
Oh, right. Hana-chan, let me take your measurements.
What are you trying to do?!
It'll only take a second. Just let me measure you.
Stay away!
If you come any closer,
I'll report you to the police.
Wh-What?! H-Hey, Hinata, help me!
Mya-nee...
My hands are softer than hers!
Don't compete with her! It'll only complicate things more!
See, Mya-nee?
I know. I get it!
But could you do something about Hana-chan over there?
She's about to call the police!
It's super easy to make Hana happy.
Really? What should I do?
If you give her food, she calms right down.
So simple! And adorable!
Once she gets like this, she'll hardly move until she's done.
Oh, you're right!
M-Maybe I'll try patting her, too...
Why...
Oh! I've got it!
I'll pat Hana, so you can just pat me, Mya-nee!
What is this situation?
It's already been a week since the day that angel flew down.
What is it, Mya-nee? Want to take a nap together?
Honestly. You're already in fifth grade.
Say, Hinata...
I-Isn't Hana-chan going to come over to visit anymore?
Hana?
Probably not.
When I asked her the other day...
If your sister isn't around, I'll go.
...is what she said.
What is this? Somehow, I feel really shocked.
Why?
Mya-nee? What's wrong?
I'll just have to get her to come over again, and this time I'll make friends for sure!
Hello?
Hinata, tell Hana-chan for me...
Hana!
Is something wrong?
Mya-nee said you should come over
on our next day off
because she'll give you yummy sweets.
That sounds like an invitation from a social deviant.
H-Hana-chan is coming to spend the night?!
Yeah.
A sleepover?
We can play lots that way!
I mean, as long as it's okay with you...
If Mom says it's okay, then it's fine with me.
Yay! Thanks, Mya-nee!
But this is the first time you've wanted one of your friends to sleep over.
I thought it might be okay if it was Hana.
Because you don't like having people in the house who aren't family.
Now that she mentioned it, that's true.
Thinking back, why did I decide that I wanted to be friends with Hana-chan?
Why do I keep wondering about Hana-chan?
Why is it only Hana-chan?
Why?
What is this funny, squirmy feeling?
If only Hana-chan would wear this for me...
No! That's never going to happen!
She's here!
C-Come in!
Thank you for having me.
Huh? What's with that shirt?
Where's Hinata?
So not cute!
Oh, um, she went out for a bit.
She said she'd be right back.
What's wrong?
Oh, nothing. Just your outfit is so not cu—
S-So cute!
Thank you so much!
He's called Higero. This is one of my favorite shirts.
R-Really...
What kind of character is that?
No, more importantly, she really came over after the way I invited her.
Listen, Hana-chan...
If a stranger offers you candy, you shouldn't go with them, okay?
It's dangerous.
Are you in any position to say that?
I'll be fine.
I'm not that stupid.
Right, of course you're not.
So, what did you mean by "yummy sweets"?
Well, it's pudding.
Pudding?!
Will she really be "fine"?
Oh, good! It seems like she likes it!
Seriously, though,
Hana-chan really is super cute...
Hana! You're already here!
Whoa! That shirt is so not cute!
Not cute?
Hinata, stop that!
Huh? Higero is not cute?
Not cute.
But Onee-san said he was cute.
Mya-nee did?
No way.
Mya-nee is good at making clothes, so she knows about that stuff.
Did you... lie?
Huh?! I... uh... H-He's very cute!
You did lie.
I know! Why don't you have Mya-nee give you something she made?
Hinata! That's a great idea!
I'd prefer to stay with Higero.
Hold on just a sec.
I'll bring you something way cuter than that horrible thing!
...horrible thing!
H-Horrible thing?
It's perfect!
She didn't even take my measurements.
What is this dress?
Mya-nee makes clothes for cosplay.
They're cute, but you can't really wear them outside.
Then why did you recommend it?
Wait, what are you doing?
You look so cute. I thought I'd take some pictures to capture the moment.
Why are you taking them from down there?
I thought they'd be better this way.
Stop it.
B-But they'll be g—
B-But... Let me take just one more!
I'm begging you!
All right. But not from down there.
Huh? Burst mode?
I'm going to change.
What? You're changing?
Then, how about this next?
No.
Then, this cat ear one...
I will never wear that.
If you do wear them, I'll give you another pudding.
I'll give you other sweets, too!
And if you wear more clothes I make in the future,
I'll give you whatever sweets you want, as many as you want!
I-If you're willing to go that far,
I might be willing... to wear them.
That's great, Hana-chan! So cute!
The cutest in the world! A total angel!
Mya-nee, your face is super red! Are you okay?
I'm not sure, but Hana-chan is so cute!
And when I think about her wearing clothes I made, I just...
I just get so excited!
Mya-nee, what about me?
You're cute too, Hinata.
Yay!
This time, Hinata, you pounce on top of Hana-chan.
Like this?
Yes!
Perfect!
What am I doing?
What a feast!
You can eat as much as you'd like.
Let's dig in!
I went through a lot for these sweets.
They're so good!
They must be expensive.
I wonder if I could buy a few with my allowance.
Say, Hinata.
Where can you buy these?
Mya-nee made all of them!
She... made these?
So I need her if I want to eat more of these?
Which means I...
I have to keep playing along with her creepy hobbies?
Creepy?!
W-Wait, as long as she's having fun, everything's fine.
H-Hana-chan, what did you just...
But if she ever gets tired of me...
I'm tired of you, Hana-chan. We're done.
I'm not giving you any more sweets, so you don't have to come anymore.
...come anymore.
Leave the sweets!
Just the sweets are enough! I don't need you!
H-Hana-chan, what's wrong?
No fair playing without me!
Let me play, too!
Hey, Mya-nee! Mya-nee!
Hinata! You're killing your sister!
Sorry, Mya-nee! Are you okay?
Y-Yes, I'm fine.
Shouldn't you go to the hospital?
R-Really, I'm fine.
Not being able to breathe was painful,
but somehow, maybe because Hana-chan was hugging me,
it was kind of nice.
You should definitely go to a hospital.
You really can eat a lot, Hana.
Well, I don't know how much longer I'll be able to eat these.
Honestly, Hana-chan,
you don't need to worry so much.
I've been thinking...
Ten years from now, even twenty years...
I'm sure I'll still be having fun dressing you up, Hana-chan!
You've been thinking something that creepy?
I think clothes like that will be a stretch in twenty years.
No, no! I'm sure you'll be able to pull it off, Hana-chan!
I'm home.
Mom! Welcome home!
Thank you for having me.
Oh, so you're Hana-chan!
Welcome.
Hinata, why don't you and Hana-chan go take a bath?
Okay!
I'll go with you—
No, no. Miyako, you sit right there.
Let's go, Hana!
Leave those here.
Man, those were yummy.
I'm jealous, Hinata. You get to eat those yummy sweets every day.
Then you should just come over every day!
Every day?
Yeah!
I could eat those every day.
But in order to do that...
Did you eat too much?
But if you ate that much every day,
you'd get fat by the time you grew up.
I-I'll exercise as much as I eat, so I'll be fine... probably.
If you exercise as much as you eat, you'll get all muscly!
I'm looking forward to seeing whether you'll be muscly or chubby when you grow up!
What are you saying?
We're having curry for dinner today!
I think I might be full.
Onee-san!
Mya-nee!
Who did this to you? Was it an enemy?
Enemy?
Not so much an enemy as a level boss.
Boss?
It was Mom, huh?
What were you thinking, feeding them sweets before dinner?
I'm sorry!
That was horrible.
I didn't think she'd leave me there for three hours.
Mya-nee, let's sleep together!
You have Hana-chan today, don't you?
That's why Hana's here, too!
Wh-What?
O... Okay.
How did this happen?
Um, Onee-san?
Yes?
It's my fault your mother got angry with you, isn't it?
I'm sorry.
No, no. I'm the one who made the sweets.
It's not your fault, Hana-chan.
So don't feel bad, okay?
Okay.
Um...
Yes?
Those clothes... you don't wear them, Onee-san?
Those clothes? You mean the cosplay stuff?
Yes. You only had me and Hinata wear them.
You're pretty, so I think they'd look nice on you.
Well, um...
M-More importantly, what did you think of the sweets today?
They were delicious.
What's wrong?
That squirmy feeling hit out of the blue!
Squirmy?
But it's not a bad feeling.
Once I accept it, it's kind of nice—
Onee-san?
She moves in her sleep too much.
I already knew about Mya-nee,
but I didn't know you moved a lot in your sleep too, Hana!
Onee-san, you sleep with Hinata a lot, don't you?
Yeah...
That must be rough.
Yeah.
sa konya mo genki ni
hajimemasho
tenshi ga maioriru jikan
jiyu kimama ni
hashaideitaino
issho ni
asobimasho
mainichi iroiro to
arukedo kyo wa zenbu poi
arukedo kyo wa zenbu poi poi
arukedo kyo wa zenbu poi poi poi
arukedo kyo wa zenbu poi poi poi poi !
minna de odoro
ryote o hiroge
ima
anata no sugu soba ni iruyo
kimamana tenshitachi
amefuri sabishi toki ni wa
egao de te o tatako
anata no sugu soba ni iruyo
tsurai toki kanashi toki
o hoshi sama kirakira egao de
ashita wa hare moyo
dokidoki o
purezento
koko dake no
himitsudayo
& Moving
Today, I'm all alone in the house.
This is my chance!
Pale...
shining...
miracle...
flower...
White Lily!
It's a little embarrassing wearing this, but...
I just can't stop!
If anyone saw me like this, I'd just di—
Why?! The house next door is supposed to be empty!
How much did she see? If she saw me do the lines...
I'll just die!
Pale, shining miracle flower...
White Lily!
Hana-chan was so cute!
What should I have her wear next time?
Something like that... Oh, or this would be good!
Next Time
"Incontestably Cute"
Next time: "Incontestably Cute."
Until then...