Oh, how do I even...
Um...
Those clothes... you don't wear them, Onee-san?
Those clothes? You mean the cosplay stuff?
Yes. You only had me and Hinata wear them.
You're pretty, so I think they'd look nice on you.
Well, um...
M-More importantly, what did
you think of the sweets today?
I managed to gloss over it, but then...
Pale, shining miracle flower...
White Lily!
I want to die.
If Hana-chan finds out I was having fun
cosplaying in secret, by myself...
Mya-nee! I'm home!
Welcome home, Hinata.
Thank you for having me, Onee-san.
Wha?! W-Welcome, Hana-chan!
Hello!
sa konya mo genki ni
hajimemasho
tenshi ga maioriru jikan
jiyu kimama ni
hashaideitaino
issho ni
asobimasho
mainichi iroiro to
arukedo kyo wa zenbu poi
arukedo kyo wa zenbu poi poi
arukedo kyo wa zenbu poi poi poi
arukedo kyo wa zenbu poi poi poi poi !
minna de odoro
ryote o hiroge
ima
anata no sugu soba ni iruyo
kimamana tenshitachi
amefuri sabishi toki ni wa
egao de te o tatako
anata no sugu soba ni iruyo
tsurai toki kanashi toki
o hoshi sama kirakira egao de
ashita wa hare moyo
dokidoki o
purezento
koko dake no
himitsudayo
Episode 2: Uncontestably Cute
Hey, guess what! This is awesome, Mya-nee!
Noa transferred in today, but here's
the real surprise! Can you believe it?
She says she moved in next door to us!
It's so awesome! Yay! Yay!
I-Is that right?
I'm Himesaka Noa.
I'm looking forward to getting
to know you, Mya-san.
Did she... come here to laugh at me?!
And I was wondering, Onee-san...
What's today's share?
Today's share?
Mya-nee gives Hana sweets in exchange
for wearing the clothes she's made.
Clothes she's made...
What a nice hobby.
But she only makes them.
She doesn't wear them, right?
Now you mention it, I've never
seen Mya-nee wearing them, either.
Really?
Is that so?
I'd love to see what kind of clothes they are.
Mya-nee, which ones are we wearing today?
Oh! That one!
That's...
It's White Lily!
It's so cute!
It's a little embarrassing...
You're not wearing it today?
Huh? N-No, I...
Just kidding!
It's your secret, right?
Don't worry, I'll keep it.
Noa-chan!
She's an angel!
In exchange, you'll do whatever I ask. Right?
She's a devil.
A-Anything?
Pale, shining miracle flower...
White Lily!
That's awesome!
What do you think? Cute, right?
Y-Yes! You're very cute!
Anyone as adorable as me
wearing these clothes,
is unbeatable!
What is this little girl saying?
That's a relief.
I was wondering what she'd ask for,
but she just wanted to cosplay.
I don't have to wear that embarrassing
outfit, but I still get sweets. I'm so lucky!
Hana-chan, you can wear it later, okay?
You're amazing! You're just
as cute as the real thing!
Right? Mya-san, Hana-chan, feel free
to praise me as much as you'd like!
Yes. You're very cute!
Yes, very cute.
Right?!
Um... Can I have the costume back now?
Okay!
Nice! Very nice! I can't get enough!
Thank you...
Thank you!
Oh, you're so cute, Hana-chan!
Now, hold it right there and
look a little to the right.
Perfect! Just like that! That's super cute!
That's nothing like how she reacted to me...
What is this? It's yummy.
Didn't I tell you not to take
them from down there?
Oh, uh, I'm sorry.
This time, raise your right
arm and strike a pose!
Great! So cute! Hana-chan!
Mya-san! Who's cuter, me or Hana-chan?
Hana-chan!
No hesitation?!
Is there such a big difference
between me and Hana-chan?
Could it be that I'm really
not that cute at all?
Papa, Mama, and all my friends might have been saying I was cute just to be nice.
Hana really is cute, isn't she?
I knew it!
But it suited you better, Noa.
I think you were cuter.
...you were cuter.
Right?!
Oh, I know!
Let's all have a cosplay contest!
A contest?
I'll show you that I'm cuter than Hana-chan.
Onee-san, a moment.
Right. Right.
Got it.
Got what?
W-Wow... Noa-chan,
you really are the cutest!
I admit complete defeat.
Oh! Good for you, Noa!
Ugh! What the heck is going on?!
What're you doing? Dancing?
Come to think of it,
because of all that happened,
I never really took a good look
at Noa-chan, but she's...
Cute.
You just looked at me
and said, "Cute," right?
Oh, uh... Yeah.
I'm cuter than Hana-chan, right?
What? I think Hana-chan is cuter.
Argh!
Okay. We're having a cosplay contest
to prove that I am uncontestably cute.
Wow!
The rules are simple.
We'll all wear Mya-san's
clothes and Mya-san will give us scores.
Sounds like fun!
G-Giving scores? I'm not sure I can...
It's too much work. I don't want to do it.
And now, let's start the cosplay contest!
Are you listening?
First up... me!
What do you think? Cute, right?
You really are cute, Noa-chan!
Just like a real idol!
Right?
Of course, my score is 100, right?
Hmm... Maybe a 98.
What about the other 2 points?!
I just thought I shouldn't
give a 100 on the first turn.
You don't need to think about
stuff the way they do for TV!
Second... Hana-chan!
What's with those clothes?
From top to bottom,
you're in Mya-san's track suit!
Are you even trying?
No.
Well, I guess this means
my victory is a sure thing.
Mya-san, the score?
Eight points!
I see you finally understand
that I'm uncontestably cute.
Oh! I'm sorry.
Infinity.
Infinity?!
Th-The fact that Hana-chan is wearing
the clothes I was just wearing...
I sense infinite potential in this!
Third... Hinata-chan.
It's Higero!
What is that creepy thing?
Higero! It's a character Hana-chan likes.
I completely forgot I made that!
She likes that creepy thing?
She really seems to like that creepy thing!
I was the only one who wore a real outfit.
There's no point in scoring these—
Why?!
Because Hana-chan is so happy.
What about Hinata-chan's score?!
Okay, say cheese!
Why am I in last place?
I guess I'm really not cute. So that's it...
I thought you were the cutest, Noa.
What?
D-Did you really think that, Hinata-chan?
Yeah!
You're the cutest, Noa!
Pit-a-pat...
Th-Thanks.
Sure!
Want to wear this?
No, I don't.
Very nice! I love that expression!
From here... Oh, and this angle, too!
Great! You're the best, Hana-chan!
I want to wear the Higero...
Finally, Mya-san, go put this on!
Huh? I-I thought I was the judge!
I told you.
Everyone is doing this cosplay contest.
I've been set up!
No, no, no, no, no, no!
I can't!
Can you look at Hana-chan and
Hinata-chan and still say that?
Huh?
Onee-san cosplaying...
Mya-nee's going to dress up, too?
Okay...
Fourth... Mya-san!
Of all the costumes,
why'd it have to be this one?
Did she plan this from the start?
To make fun of me?
Mya-nee, you're so cute!
I agree.
Y-You don't have to say those
things just to be nice!
I know I don't look good in it!
You look cute.
You do! You're even cuter than Noa!
Huh?
Hinata, let me borrow that.
Huh? Sure.
What do you think?
You said you'd keep it a secret.
I kept what you did yesterday a secret.
Thank you for that.
But it's more fun wearing it with everyone
than wearing it alone, right?
Yeah.
Noa-chan, you're... how can I put it?
What? Cute?
Yes. You're very cute.
Right?
I really am the greatest!
Mya-nee really is the greatest!
What?
Himesaka Noa
I slept too much.
Why do I feel like I've missed out
when I sleep in until afternoon?
Hinata-chan, just give up already.
Dang it!
Hinata?
Oh, Mya-nee. You're up?
What are you doing?
Playing tag!
In the house?
Yeah!
You should play outside.
Onee-san, you probably don't know since you were sleeping,
but it's raining today.
Oh. Is it?
Yes.
So, I was "it", and I caught Hana-chan,
and I trapped Hinata-chan too, but...
You're not catching me that easily!
And that's why you climbed the walls.
Yeah!
You should really just give up.
Besides, if you play tag in this house,
you know it will come after you.
Don't worry, she's not home right now!
That's not the problem.
Play tag with us, Mya-nee!
I'm not playing.
Okay, we can play dodgeball instead!
In the house?
Leapfrog, then!
I can just see the sliding
screens getting broken.
Then how about hide-and-seek?
Hide-and-seek might be all right.
Okay! Hide-and-seek it is!
Rock, paper, scissors!
You're "it" Noa.
Aw...
I ended up playing.
I wanted to go hide...
Noa-chan, what is this?
Everyone hide while I'm singing, okay?
Huh? You're going to sing?
Go round and round, merry-go-round!
Come on, Mya-nee! We're hiding!
I'm the greatest in the world!
So cute, cute, cute...
La, la, la...
Playing hide-and-seek at my age...
She'll probably find me
right away, but...why not?
Oh, she stopped. She sang a whole song.
Thank you, everyone!
Encore! Encore!
Oh, well, I guess there's no helping it!
What's this little act she's doing?
Really?
O-Onee-san...
You were hiding here?
Y-Yes...
I'm sorry. Do you mind if I hide here, too?
Huh?
N-No, I don't mind.
Thank you.
Y-You were looking for a hiding place
right up until the last second, huh?
No. I went to the bathroom first.
So carefree...
La, la, la...
Thank you, everyone!
Okay, it's time to go looking!
Noa...
Hinata-chan! Are you okay?
I thought that if I climbed up
to where I was before,
you'd never find me.
The way you give everything your all
is one of the things I like about you.
But I was waiting for your song to end,
and now I can't move my arms!
I think they're broken!
Don't worry. They're not broken!
I'm sorry I took so long.
Oh! They're all better since
you rubbed them for me!
I'll search with you!
Okay!
Where could Mya-nee and Hana be hiding?
Leave it to me.
If I call Hana-chan with this phone,
we'll discover her location in no time!
Hana-chan
Wow! You're a genius!
What is it?
It's nothing.
Noa seems like the type to call my cell phone, so I'm turning it off.
Please turn yours off, too.
Cell phone?
Wait... where did I leave mine?
Oh. It doesn't ring very often, does it?
Hana-chan...
Neither one is ringing...
Leave it to me this time, Noa!
Hinata-chan!
The scent should lure Hana out.
She'd have to be really dumb
to come out because of this.
No! Don't, Hana-chan!
Huh? Ow!
Uh... What is it?
Onee-san, you smell sweet.
Oh... it's because I was baking a cake.
Huh...
It smells nice.
...smells nice.
Hana-chan is...
Hana-chan is...!
Onee-san, your heart is beating really fast.
You don't need to be so nervous.
It's just hide-and-seek.
That's true...
This has nothing to do with hide-and-seek!
What a delicious smell...
I can't take it anymore!
Onee-san?!
Oh...
If Mom finds out about this...
M-Mom?
Welcome home.
What are you doing?! And at your age!
"It" caught us, so hide-and-seek was over.
Mya-nee! I'm coming in, too!
Jeez, Hinata...
Sorry, Mya-nee. Mom got mad at you again.
I'm fine. Don't worry.
Tearing the door was bad, though.
But today was so much fun!
I had fun, too! Noa-chan's a nice girl.
I know, right?
I'm glad that it's Noa
who moved in next door!
I wonder if Noa-chan's taking a bath, too.
Hana and Noa are coming
over to play again tomorrow.
Today's the day I will prove it to you!
Huh?
I'm the one who's uncontestably cute!
To that end... ta-da!
Take a Picture of the Uncontestably Cute Me!
Uncontestably Cute Me !
Take a Picture of the
Everyone takes
pictures of me
and the cutest
shot wins !
Uncontestably Cute Me !
Take a Picture of the
Everyone takes
pictures of me
and the cutest
shot wins !
Everyone will take pictures of me,
and the most indisputably cute shot wins!
Uncontestably Cute Me !
Take a Picture of the
Everyone takes
pictures of me
and the cutest
shot wins !
So we're not competing with you this time?
Uncontestably Cute Me !
Take a Picture of the
Everyone takes
pictures of me
and the cutest
shot wins !
Uncontestably Cute Me !
Take a Picture of the
Everyone takes
pictures of me
and the cutest
shot wins !
Uncontestably Cute Me !
Take a Picture of the
Everyone takes
pictures of me
and the cutest
shot wins !
I realized something.
It's a given that I am the cutest, so...
the only one I need to surpass is myself!
She just said something
you'd see in a battle manga!
Plus, if Mya-san's the judge,
Hana-chan will always win.
That's the thing.
Well, you know...
Let's get started!
First up... Hana-chan!
What kind of pose do you want?
I can do anything!
Oh, just hold still for a second.
Okay.
Isn't that a little too casual?!
Take a cute picture!
Don't worry. It's fine.
What do you mean, "fine"?
Take a cute picture of me!
It's fine because, no matter what,
any picture of you will be cute.
Well, that's true!
Second... Mya-san!
Take a picture of me just
like you did with Hana-chan!
Um... In that case...
If you could look down a little...
Good, and if you could hold the curtain...
Just like that. Okay.
I'm taking the picture!
That's not it!
When you take pictures of
Hana-chan, you're a lot creepier!
Huh?
Third... Hinata-chan!
Leave it to me, Noa!
I'll take a really cute shot.
Hinata-chan!
You're the only one who's taking
this seriously, Hinata-chan!
If you wear this, I can
take a super cute picture.
Oh, what is it? What is it?
It must be cute.
Here!
It's what my beloved Mya-nee
is always wearing!
What do we do? Noa-chan looks depressed!
For now, let's try flattering her.
That usually lifts her spirits.
Hinata, would you be the first
to try to lift Noa's spirits?
Got it.
Huh? What's going on?
We didn't mean you should lift her!
What's going on, Hinata-chan?
Do you feel better, Noa?
Honestly, how would this
make me feel better?
Oh.
What is it?
I just thought...
she might be uncontestably cute right now.
asa tobiokite
mado o aketara
kao o aratte
hamigaki o shite
sa wan tsu suri
de tobide sou
osharena fuku o kite
okashi o tariagete
nakayoku te o tsunaide
minna de koeawase
duwaduwa
duwaduwa sa
odoro
ikuyo
itsumo happi happi furenzu
zutto happi happi furenzu
karada wa ukiuki
sumairu shinagara
motto happi happi furenzu
minna happi happi furenzu
todoke doko made mo
istumo happi happi furenzu
zutto happi happi furenzu
kokoro wa wakuwaku
minna sukippu shinagara
motto happi happi furenzu
minna happi happi furenzu
kyo mo ashita mo zutto
watashitachi minna tomodachi sa
I'm leaving now!
Good morning!
Hello. Good morning.
Kanon! Koyori!
Morning!
Yes... very cute, Noa-chan.
You're the best!
Right?
Wait, what are you looking at, Mya-san?
Hana-chan is such an angel!
Oh, honestly!
Next time: "Imprinting"
Be sure to watch!