Year 5
Class 3
Today we'll be making original
board games in groups.
Making a Board Game
Talk to each other and decide
on a theme before you start.
A board game, huh? Sounds like fun!
Now, I'll let the class reps handle the rest.
Right!
We'll hand out the drawing paper now.
We laid out the markers and scissors already,
so each group should take a set.
If there's anything you don't understand,
you can ask us, your class reps!
Question! Kanon, can the theme be anything?
Yes, it can.
Huh?
Kanon-chan!
Kanon!
Why's everyone only asking Kanon?
Ask me, too!
Koyori, what would be an
example of a good theme?
An example?
Um...
Uh-huh...
If the theme is something you like,
or someone you're close to,
it'll be easy to make into a game!
Is Koyori-chan satisfied with that?
Someone close...
What should we make the theme of our game?
I know! My cuteness!
Rejected. Sit down.
Sadness...
I know!
Mya-nee!
Huh?
WATATEN!:
an Angel Flew Down to Me
sa konya mo genki ni
hajimemasho
tenshi ga maioriru jikan
jiyu kimama ni
hashaideitaino
issho ni
asobimasho
mainichi iroiro to
arukedo kyo wa zenbu poi
arukedo kyo wa zenbu poi poi
arukedo kyo wa zenbu poi poi poi
arukedo kyo wa zenbu poi poi poi poi !
minna de odoro
ryote o hiroge
ima
anata no sugu soba ni iruyo
kimamana tenshitachi
amefuri sabishi toki ni wa
egao de te o tatako
anata no sugu soba ni iruyo
tsurai toki kanashi toki
o hoshi sama kirakira egao de
ashita wa hare moyo
dokidoki o
purezento
koko dake no
himitsudayo
Making a Board Game
Episode 3: Imprinting
It's decided. The theme is Mya-nee!
How are we going to make that into a game?
I dunno.
I dunno, but...
I want to make Mya-nee into
an awesome board game!
Mya-nee-san is the big sister
you're always talking about, right?
Yup! That's right!
Your kind, smart, pretty,
amazing older sister, right?
What?
That's right! Mya-nee is amazing!
Amazing...
I'd like to see your game when it's done.
Sure thing!
Are we okay with this?
Why not?
If there's anything you don't
understand while you're making it,
you can ask me anything.
I'll teach you!
Kanon-chan!
Kanon!
Seriously! Ask me questions, too!
Hey! Me, too!
What do you think about
this for the Mya-nee Game?
Wow!
This is...
I like it! It's great, Noa!
We made a board game with you as the theme!
What does that mean?
High five
hands
head
the
Pat on
Shake
Give
hug
them a
Give a
Complement
say hello
Smile and
First, the three of us will play the game.
High five
hands
head
the
Pat on
Shake
Give
hug
them a
Give a
Complement
say hello
Smile and
High five
hands
head
the
Pat on
Shake
Give
hug
them a
Complement
say hello
Smile and
High five
hands
Shake
Ta-da!
Just watch from there, Onee-san.
We take turns rolling the dice and
move forward that number of spaces!
And on certain spots,
there are things you have to do.
You'll do those, Mya-nee.
Me?
Shouldn't the person who
landed on the space do it?
But we made the game for you.
If you don't do it, there's no point.
Yeah, but...
Give the person who
stopped here a hug!
Th-This is...
Come on, Mya-nee, just do it!
I-I-I-I-If Hana-chan stopped here...
Hurry up, Mya-san!
But if you don't want to play,
there's nothing we can do about it.
Let's play! Let's play!
Honestly, I don't want to play, either.
Let's just not—
Let's play, everyone!
Yay!
So I'll go, then Noa, then Hana, okay?
Leave it to me!
Leave it to you?
Well, I guess we can try it.
Here I go!
There!
One, two, three, four, five!
Smile and
say hello
Smile and say hello!
Okay, Mya-nee!
I was wondering what kind of crazy
thing they might have me do, but...
"Smile and say hello."
They really are just kids.
Wait... Huh?
H-H-He—
This is a lot more embarrassing
than I thought!
Huh?
"Smile and say hello." It's so simple,
an elementary schooler can do it.
Surely even I should be
able to handle this much?
Findings
In class, she is...
excellent grades and...
However, greeting people is...
communication skills could be...
In elementary school, my report card
did say I couldn't greet people.
But I'm an adult now!
And I'm not saying it to a stranger or a
classmate. It's Hana-chan and her friends!
Even I can do that!
Uh, wait... Please don't
look at me like that.
Being the center of attention makes me...
To think... I can't even greet people...
I'm just... I...
Mya-san is crying, so we'll
move on to the next one.
There!
Give a compliment
One, two, three!
Give a compliment!
Mya-san, you can compliment me now!
Ah. Okay. You're cute. Very cute.
Look at me when you say it.
Whoa... You're too close!
Say it!
You're cute! Really cute! Please let go now!
I'm not letting go until
you say it 100 times!
That's like something a really
needy girlfriend would say!
Come on! You've got 96 more times to go.
Doesn't look like Mya-nee's gonna be
able to handle it. Let's move on.
Okay.
One, two, three, four, five, six...
Oh.
Give a hug.
What?!
T-T-T-To think Hana-chan actually
landed on it! I'm so lucky!
N-Now, Hana-chan and I can...
I'm feeling threatened. Can we not do this?
There there...
Onee-san, if you could
back away for a moment...
It'll be fine.
I'll be gentle.
Just back away.
Just leave everything to me, Hana-chan!
I said, back off!
Uh... I'm sorry. It just sort of happened.
But please stop.
In its own way, this is kinda...
Next up is me again!
Um, w-wait just a second.
What is it?
Isn't this board game a little odd?
Why am I the only one doing these things?
Huh? Because we made this board game
to help you get over your shyness.
Huh?
Wow!
This is...
I like it! It's great, Noa!
So we'll have Mya-nee play this, right?
That's right.
I thought maybe this kind of
thing could work for her.
Yeah! It'd be nice if Mya-nee
could do stuff like this!
At this point, can't we just say it's
a board game to rehabilitate her?
Sounds good! Let's do it!
We got an "excellent work" from the teacher!
Theme: "Mya-nee"
Title: "Mya-nee Rehabilitation Board Game"
Excellent Work
Tell us we did good!
You made that at school?
Hinata insisted, so we made it.
What do you think? Does it seem
like it might cure your shyness?
Yeah... I sort of can't think
about that right now.
What have you done? What must
that teacher think of me?!
Instead of worrying about that,
think about the fact that you've forced your
little sister to make something like this.
When you put it like that,
there's nothing else I can say.
Shake
hands
Give the person who
stopped here a hug!
Pat on
the head
High five
Okay!
Hinata, your big sis is
going to do her best!
I'll try really hard so you won't
have to worry about me anymore.
Mya-nee!
Yeah!
Starting tomorrow!
I can't seem to feel the
motivation today either, so...
I'll start tomorrow.
WATATEN!:
an Angel Flew Down to Me
Mya-nee! Can I sleep with you tonight?
Not tonight.
Aw, why not?
Hana-chan and Noa-chan are
coming tomorrow, right?
So I want to finish this.
I'll be up late tonight,
so you should go to bed first.
What is it?
Nothing.
Here it comes!
Got it!
Last night, Mya-nee wouldn't
let me sleep with her.
Hup! Got it! There! Got it!
You sleep with Mya-san every night?
Not every night, but...
If it were every night, I don't
think her sister would last.
You really love Mya-san, don't you?
Yeah! I love Mya-nee the most!
Why do you love her so much
when she's like that?
Why?
I dunno.
I dunno, but I love Mya-nee the most!
How long have you been so
attached to your sister?
Huh?
How long?
I dunno, but I've loved
Mya-nee the most forever!
This kind of thing is called...
imprinting, right?
What kind of sweets do you
think we'll have today?
I hope it's something chocolate.
I think I'd like cookies.
Chocolate cookies, then.
Sounds good!
Yes, it does.
Hinata-chan! Let's go home!
Huh?
Yeah!
Let's see, let's see.
What should I make today?
Huh?
Caution.
Do not eat too much.—Mom
Mom...
Hmm... A bar of chocolate.
Oh!
Stop! Hana! Noa!
Huh?
A virus is running rampant
outside the shadows.
If you leave the shadows...
you'll instantly die!
Where in the world did this come from?
It's a game to get home
without leaving the shadows!
Sounds like fun!
What kind of game is that?
In the sun is a virus...
Oh!
Hinata means "in the sun," so the Hinata
virus is spreading and causing instant death!
But it's calm in the shadows.
Is that a play on words?
It makes it sound like you're
the source of the virus.
And with that set-up, we can't
leave the shadows at all.
Huh? Then...
Outside the shadows is a field of flowers.
Don't step on them!
Like a fairy tale!
But if we start here,
we can't get to the other side.
Leave that to me!
There!
Wait! Why are you throwing that?
If there aren't any shadows,
we just make some!
Oh! You use your backpack
to create a shadow!
Hinata-chan, you're amazing!
Hup!
I made a shadow!
Okay!
Hup!
I hope this will make them happy.
Stop
Okay!
Next, this street...
There are no shadows here, either.
I'll make a shadow.
Huh?
If you do that, you'll be...
Don't worry about me.
Hana!
Hana-chan... You aren't just doing something
heroic to get out of playing, are you?
I'll leave the rest to you.
Next up... the finishing touches!
You don't need to make a shadow, Hana.
We can just ask someone passing by!
Leave it to me!
If I ask, super cute as I am,
it'll be a piece of cake!
Excuse me, miss!
Hm? Me?
She's adorable.
Um, so...
Will you be my shadow?
Shadow?
All you have to do is cross here with us.
Please?
Sorry about this.
O-Okay.
Yay!
Thank you very much!
So... that was all you needed? Bye, then...
See? We got across
thanks to my cuteness, right?
I guess we did.
Now that we've come this far,
it's only a little more to my house.
Oh, Hinata. You can't be there.
Huh?
Hinata, don't chase it! It's dangerous!
Hinata-chan!
So she's this tired because
she ran after it.
Yes.
Hinata... Like Hana-chan said,
running near cars is dangerous.
Don't ever do it again, okay?
I'm sorry.
Mya-san is the only one who
can make Hinata behave.
A well-behaved Hinata virus...
Ah, so calming...
Because she hides in the shadows!
Huh? Are you talking about me?
Mya-nee! Mya-nee!
So, Onee-san, what about today's sweets?
Mya-nee!
I made some!
Oh, and I made some new outfits!
Yay! I wonder what today's will be!
I'm so excited!
Yay! Chocolate cookies!
And...
Will you wear this one today?
Yes! Me! Me! Me! I'll wear it!
Super cute me will wear it for you!
Don't worry! I made one
for you, too, Noa-chan.
Yay!
Mya-nee! Where's mine? Where's mine?
Oh, I'm sorry. I ran out of time
and couldn't make one for you.
Next time, okay?
Huh?
That's great, both of you!
It looks good on you! So cute!
Right?
Hana-chan, look this way!
Mya-nee, should I wear something, too?
Noa-chan, just hold that.
Hey, Mya-nee, what about me?
Oh, I love that face!
Hinata, do you have a sec?
Huh?
What is it, Mya-nee?
I want more light. Can you draw the curtain?
You're so cute! Both of you!
Nice! Very nice!
Hinata?
Mya-nee... you stupid jerk!
What?!
Hey! What do you think you're doing?
Mya-nee, you're unfit for society!
Where did you learn that phrase?
Honestly, where did that come from?
What happened?
You really are an idiot, Onee-san.
Huh? What do you mean, Hana-chan?
Um... a deadbeat?
Is that how you think of me?
I'm going home for today.
Okay.
May I have the cookies to take with me?
Oh. Yes.
Thank you for having us!
Hinata...
Hinata, why are you sulking?
Guess there's no helping it.
If you tell me why you're sulking,
I might let you sleep with me tonight.
And maybe we could take a bath together.
Really?
So...
Why are you sulking, Hinata?
Because you only pay
attention to Hana and Noa.
You don't pay any attention to me.
Like today, I was the
only one with no outfit.
That's true. Today wasn't very good.
But... when Hana-chan and
Noa-chan aren't around,
I play with her a lot.
Mya-nee!
Mya-nee, you stupid jerk!
Why did it turn out like this today?
Hinata.
Come here.
What for?
Okay, Hinata. There, there...
Mom, let me hold her, too!
Will you be okay?
Yeah!
Hinata, come to your big sis!
I'm your big sister, Hinata!
Mya! Mya!
Hinata!
Mya!
Hinata has been like this
ever since she was born.
Hinata, I'm sorry about today.
Okay. I can sleep with you tonight, right?
Yes.
Mya-nee!
Let's play until bedtime!
Okay. What will we play?
I want to move around! I'm itching to go!
Okay, but we can't go outside.
Pick something we can do inside.
Oh!
That's it! Pro wrestling!
Let's play pro wrestling!
Pro wrestling isn't a good idea...
Boxing would work, too!
You're just trying to beat me up, aren't you?
Are you still angry?
It's been so long since
I slept with Mya-nee!
I let you sleep with me at least
once every three days.
I'd like to do it every day, though.
Hinata, are you trying to kill me?
Mya-nee! Let's sleep together!
Okay.
Again?
Mya-nee!
Mya-nee...
Hinata...
asa tobiokite
mado o aketara
kao o aratte
hamigaki o shite
sa wan tsu suri
de tobide sou
osharena fuku o kite
okashi o tariagete
nakayoku te o tsunaide
minna de koeawase
duwaduwa
duwaduwa sa
odoro
ikuyo
itsumo happi happi furenzu
zutto happi happi furenzu
karada wa ukiuki
sumairu shinagara
motto happi happi furenzu
minna happi happi furenzu
todoke doko made mo
istumo happi happi furenzu
zutto happi happi furenzu
kokoro wa wakuwaku
minna sukippu shinagara
motto happi happi furenzu
minna happi happi furenzu
kyo mo ashita mo zutto
watashitachi minna tomodachi sa
So you made up with your sister?
Yeah! We take a bath together every day
and sleep together every night!
Onee-san, thank you for all of your hard work.
It must be nice having a big sister.
I'm an only child.
Huh?
Mya... Mya-nee is my big sister, but...
Y-You can borrow her
sometimes, if you want.
I don't want her.
Noa-chan's here.
Look! Look!
Papa bought me a super cute bathing suit!
Cute, right?
Wow!
Mya-nee, let's take a bath together!
Let's sleep together!
Let's sleep together today
and tomorrow and forever!
Hinata, j-just a second...
Next time...
"Can We Speak For a Moment?"
Mya-nee! Let's watch together!